<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <channel>
        <title>Linux Kamarada</title>
        <description>The Linux Kamarada Project is a new project that aims to spread and promote Linux as a robust, secure, versatile and easy to use operating system, suitable for everyday usage be at home, at work or on the server. The project focuses mainly on distribution and documentation.
</description>
        
            <language>en</language>
        
        <link>https://kamarada.github.io/en/</link>
        <atom:link href="https://kamarada.github.io/en/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
        <pubDate>Wed, 25 Jan 2017 08:23:16 -0200</pubDate>
        <lastBuildDate>Wed, 25 Jan 2017 08:23:16 -0200</lastBuildDate>
        <generator>Jekyll v2.5.3</generator>
        
        
            <item>
                <title>How to install openSUSE Leap Linux on a server</title>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;When I say &lt;a href=&quot;/en/2016/11/16/optimal-release-for-linux-professionals-arrives-with-opensuse-leap-42-2/&quot;&gt;openSUSE Leap&lt;/a&gt; is a mature and stable Linux distribution, I&amp;#39;m not talking about other distributions&amp;#39; concept of stability: old software that has been frozen, thoroughly tested and fixed. Each new openSUSE Leap release brings very fresh software components (released within the same month or year) that work well together. That is the result of the technology and effort employed in developing the distribution, which works fine on home desktops, workstations and also on &lt;strong&gt;servers&lt;/strong&gt;!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&#39;image no-ads-here text-center&#39; itemscope itemtype=&#39;http://schema.org/ImageObject&#39;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#39;/files/2017/01/opensuse-server-01.jpg&#39; title=&#39;&#39;&gt;
&lt;img src=&#39;/files/2017/01/opensuse-server-01.jpg&#39; alt=&#39;&#39; class=&#39;img-responsive img-thumbnail&#39; itemprop=&#39;contentUrl&#39;&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In this post you are going to see how to install and set up a server with openSUSE Leap. This howto resembles that on &lt;a href=&quot;/en/2016/11/15/how-to-install-opensuse-leap-linux/&quot;&gt;how to install openSUSE on a desktop&lt;/a&gt;. They differ only by the differences between desktops and servers and by the text mode, which is the preferred way of using servers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Before installation&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Before starting, there are a few things you should be aware of.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;openSUSE Leap supports a large variety of hardware devices. 32-bit processors are an exception to the rule: &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.reddit.com/r/openSUSE/comments/3d711c/will_leap_42_support_32bit_machines_given_that/&quot;&gt;they are not supported anymore&lt;/a&gt;, but servers equipped with 64-bit processors are already very common.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I could talk about the &lt;a href=&quot;https://doc.opensuse.org/documentation/leap/startup/html/book.opensuse.startup/art.opensuse.installquick.html#sec.osuse.installquick.sysreqs&quot;&gt;system requirements&lt;/a&gt; for using openSUSE. But, if it already runs smoothly on desktops, what about servers, which are much bigger in numbers (processor&amp;#39;s clock rate and number of cores, memory and hard disk, etc). Linux, in general, is a lightweight system.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here I&amp;#39;m going to recommend specifications for &amp;quot;a good start&amp;quot;:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;2GB of RAM;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;10GB hard disk; and&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;if possible, a dual core processor.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Since network environments differ dramatically, it is difficult to recommend with precision how you should size your server hardware. Observe that the specs I suggested above can be achieved even with an ordinary computer and may be more than enough for some services but not suitable for others.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If the new server will only serve DHCP, the specs above are more than necessary. If you are setting up a firewall for a home or small office network, those specs are adequate too. But if you need a file server or a web server, depending on the expected number of concurrent accesses and the size of the files, pages or downloads being served, the specs above may be insufficient.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As a rule of thumb, you should always try to size your server beyond what you need today. For example, if you estimate that 9GB is enough to store your files today, it is wrong to think that the above setup (10GB hard disk) is enough. Your new file server should have a hard disk of 20GB or more so it may suffice for a few years.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you are going to install openSUSE Leap on a virtual machine, it&amp;#39;s easy to resize specs as needed. openSUSE can be installed as a guest system on top of various &lt;a href=&quot;https://doc.opensuse.org/documentation/leap/virtualization/html/book.virt/cha.virt.support.html#virt.support.hosts&quot;&gt;virtualization hosts (hypervisors)&lt;/a&gt;, including &lt;a href=&quot;http://xenserver.org/&quot;&gt;XenServer&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.vmware.com/products/vsphere-hypervisor.html&quot;&gt;VMware vSphere&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;#39;m gonna leave the link for the &lt;a href=&quot;https://doc.opensuse.org/documentation/leap/startup/html/book.opensuse.startup/art.opensuse.installquick.html#sec.osuse.installquick.sysreqs&quot;&gt;openSUSE minimum system requirements&lt;/a&gt; for those who are curious to check them (on &lt;a href=&quot;/en/2016/11/15/how-to-install-opensuse-leap-linux/&quot;&gt;an earlier post&lt;/a&gt;, I have already mentioned the requirements for using openSUSE on a desktop).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Make sure your server is connected to the Internet and protected against power outages by a nobreak. Let&amp;#39;s get it started.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Getting started&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As we are installing openSUSE on a server, I recommend you to use the official network installation medium instead of the Linux Kamarada &lt;a href=&quot;/en/2015/12/09/what-is-a-livecd-dvd-usb/&quot;&gt;LiveDVD&lt;/a&gt; (not that it does not serve our purpose, just it&amp;#39;s not the most appropriate media for that).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To download the network installation medium, go to the openSUSE&amp;#39;s official website at &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.opensuse.org&quot;&gt;www.opensuse.org&lt;/a&gt;, hover over &lt;strong&gt;Leap&lt;/strong&gt; and click on &lt;strong&gt;Install Leap&lt;/strong&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&#39;image no-ads-here text-center&#39; itemscope itemtype=&#39;http://schema.org/ImageObject&#39;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#39;/files/2017/01/opensuse-server-02-en.jpg&#39; title=&#39;&#39;&gt;
&lt;img src=&#39;/files/2017/01/opensuse-server-02-en.jpg&#39; alt=&#39;&#39; class=&#39;img-responsive img-thumbnail&#39; itemprop=&#39;contentUrl&#39;&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Close to &lt;strong&gt;Network&lt;/strong&gt;, click on &lt;strong&gt;Direct Link&lt;/strong&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&#39;image no-ads-here text-center&#39; itemscope itemtype=&#39;http://schema.org/ImageObject&#39;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#39;/files/2017/01/opensuse-server-03-en.jpg&#39; title=&#39;&#39;&gt;
&lt;img src=&#39;/files/2017/01/opensuse-server-03-en.jpg&#39; alt=&#39;&#39; class=&#39;img-responsive img-thumbnail&#39; itemprop=&#39;contentUrl&#39;&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Select &lt;strong&gt;Save File&lt;/strong&gt; and click on &lt;strong&gt;OK&lt;/strong&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&#39;image no-ads-here text-center&#39; itemscope itemtype=&#39;http://schema.org/ImageObject&#39;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#39;/files/2017/01/opensuse-server-04-en.jpg&#39; title=&#39;&#39;&gt;
&lt;img src=&#39;/files/2017/01/opensuse-server-04-en.jpg&#39; alt=&#39;&#39; class=&#39;img-responsive img-thumbnail&#39; itemprop=&#39;contentUrl&#39;&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Your browser will start downloading the network installation medium:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&#39;image no-ads-here text-center&#39; itemscope itemtype=&#39;http://schema.org/ImageObject&#39;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#39;/files/2017/01/opensuse-server-05-en.jpg&#39; title=&#39;&#39;&gt;
&lt;img src=&#39;/files/2017/01/opensuse-server-05-en.jpg&#39; alt=&#39;&#39; class=&#39;img-responsive img-thumbnail&#39; itemprop=&#39;contentUrl&#39;&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It should not take too long, since that media contains just a minimal system, which is used only to boot the server, download and start the installer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After finished downloading the installation medium, let&amp;#39;s check its integrity: still at the &lt;a href=&quot;https://software.opensuse.org/422/en&quot;&gt;openSUSE Leap 42.2 official downloads page&lt;/a&gt;, close to &lt;strong&gt;Network&lt;/strong&gt;, click on &lt;strong&gt;SHA256 checksum&lt;/strong&gt;. The checksum file should be downloaded at the same folder where was downloaded the installation medium.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then, open a terminal on that folder and run:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-text&quot; data-lang=&quot;text&quot;&gt;$ sha256sum -c openSUSE-Leap-42.2-NET-x86_64.iso.sha256
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That command should return something like:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-text&quot; data-lang=&quot;text&quot;&gt;openSUSE-Leap-42.2-NET-x86_64.iso: OK
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Indicating that you have got a file identical to the original one, i.e. the download was not corrupted.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now, burn the ISO image you just downloaded to a CD or DVD and insert it in your server DVD drive. Or, if your server is actually a virtual machine, load the ISO image into the virtual DVD drive. Then, in both cases, restart your server.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Within moments, you will see the bootloader menu:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&#39;image no-ads-here text-center&#39; itemscope itemtype=&#39;http://schema.org/ImageObject&#39;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#39;/files/2017/01/opensuse-server-06.jpg&#39; title=&#39;&#39;&gt;
&lt;img src=&#39;/files/2017/01/opensuse-server-06.jpg&#39; alt=&#39;&#39; class=&#39;img-responsive img-thumbnail&#39; itemprop=&#39;contentUrl&#39;&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you want, you can change the &lt;strong&gt;Language&lt;/strong&gt; that will be used during installation: hit &lt;strong&gt;F2&lt;/strong&gt;, then select the desired language using the &lt;strong&gt;arrow&lt;/strong&gt; keys and hit &lt;strong&gt;Enter&lt;/strong&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&#39;image no-ads-here text-center&#39; itemscope itemtype=&#39;http://schema.org/ImageObject&#39;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#39;/files/2017/01/opensuse-server-07.jpg&#39; title=&#39;&#39;&gt;
&lt;img src=&#39;/files/2017/01/opensuse-server-07.jpg&#39; alt=&#39;&#39; class=&#39;img-responsive img-thumbnail&#39; itemprop=&#39;contentUrl&#39;&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The bootloader menu gets translated into the language you selected.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This tutorial assumes you will continue with the &lt;strong&gt;English (US)&lt;/strong&gt; language (default).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Similarly, hit &lt;strong&gt;F3&lt;/strong&gt; to switch the &lt;strong&gt;Video Mode&lt;/strong&gt; to &lt;strong&gt;Text Mode&lt;/strong&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&#39;image no-ads-here text-center&#39; itemscope itemtype=&#39;http://schema.org/ImageObject&#39;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#39;/files/2017/01/opensuse-server-08-en.jpg&#39; title=&#39;&#39;&gt;
&lt;img src=&#39;/files/2017/01/opensuse-server-08-en.jpg&#39; alt=&#39;&#39; class=&#39;img-responsive img-thumbnail&#39; itemprop=&#39;contentUrl&#39;&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hit &lt;strong&gt;F4&lt;/strong&gt;, and in &lt;strong&gt;Network Config&lt;/strong&gt; choose &lt;strong&gt;DHCP&lt;/strong&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&#39;image no-ads-here text-center&#39; itemscope itemtype=&#39;http://schema.org/ImageObject&#39;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#39;/files/2017/01/opensuse-server-09-en.png&#39; title=&#39;&#39;&gt;
&lt;img src=&#39;/files/2017/01/opensuse-server-09-en.png&#39; alt=&#39;&#39; class=&#39;img-responsive img-thumbnail&#39; itemprop=&#39;contentUrl&#39;&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Usually server network settings are set up by hand. But my own experience was that I was not able to inform the network settings at boot time, because when I pressed the slash key (&lt;strong&gt;/&lt;/strong&gt;) to type the network prefix (e.g. &lt;code&gt;192.168.25.100/24&lt;/code&gt;) actually nothing showed up. Probably that happened because the bootloader did not properly recognize my keyboard layout. So, to make things easier, I decided to use DHCP by now, leaving the proper network configuration for later.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Finally, on the bootloader menu, select &lt;strong&gt;Installation&lt;/strong&gt; and hit &lt;strong&gt;Enter&lt;/strong&gt; to start the installer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;1) Language, keyboard layout and license&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On the first screen, you are presented to the language and keyboard layout settings and the &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.opensuse.org/openSUSE:License&quot;&gt;openSUSE Leap license&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&#39;image no-ads-here text-center&#39; itemscope itemtype=&#39;http://schema.org/ImageObject&#39;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#39;/files/2017/01/opensuse-server-10-en.jpg&#39; title=&#39;&#39;&gt;
&lt;img src=&#39;/files/2017/01/opensuse-server-10-en.jpg&#39; alt=&#39;&#39; class=&#39;img-responsive img-thumbnail&#39; itemprop=&#39;contentUrl&#39;&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Check that the language and keyboard layout settings are as desired.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On text mode, you are not able to interact with the installer using the mouse, just the keyboard. To move from one field to the next, you can use the &lt;strong&gt;Tab&lt;/strong&gt; key.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Note that each field label has a highlighted letter (&lt;strong&gt;L&lt;/strong&gt;anguage, &lt;strong&gt;K&lt;/strong&gt;eyboard Layout, K&lt;strong&gt;e&lt;/strong&gt;yboard Test, &lt;strong&gt;N&lt;/strong&gt;ext, etc.). You can also select a field by pressing the &lt;strong&gt;Alt&lt;/strong&gt; key together with its label highlighted letter. For instance, use the &lt;strong&gt;Alt + L&lt;/strong&gt; key combination to access the &lt;strong&gt;L&lt;/strong&gt;anguage field.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To open a dropdown menu (such as &lt;strong&gt;Language&lt;/strong&gt; or &lt;strong&gt;Keyboard Layout&lt;/strong&gt;), select the desired menu and hit the &lt;strong&gt;down arrow&lt;/strong&gt; key. Select an option using the &lt;strong&gt;up and down arrow&lt;/strong&gt; keys and then confirm using the &lt;strong&gt;Enter&lt;/strong&gt; key.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The installer offers a text field in which you can type something to test your keyboard.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You don&amp;#39;t need to worry about the software license: since openSUSE is a &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.gnu.org/philosophy/free-sw.en.html&quot;&gt;software &lt;em&gt;libre&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, its license does not limit your use. You can read it just to know your rights as an openSUSE user. To do so, hit &lt;strong&gt;Tab&lt;/strong&gt; until the &lt;strong&gt;License Agreement&lt;/strong&gt; text area seems highlited and use the &lt;strong&gt;up and down arrow&lt;/strong&gt; keys or the &lt;strong&gt;Page Up&lt;/strong&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;Page Down&lt;/strong&gt; keys to scroll the text up or downwards, respectively.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When you finish, select &lt;strong&gt;Next&lt;/strong&gt; and hit &lt;strong&gt;Enter&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;2) Installation options&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;div class=&#39;image no-ads-here text-center&#39; itemscope itemtype=&#39;http://schema.org/ImageObject&#39;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#39;/files/2017/01/opensuse-server-11-en.jpg&#39; title=&#39;&#39;&gt;
&lt;img src=&#39;/files/2017/01/opensuse-server-11-en.jpg&#39; alt=&#39;&#39; class=&#39;img-responsive img-thumbnail&#39; itemprop=&#39;contentUrl&#39;&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On that screen, you have got two choices:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Add Online Repositories Before Installation&lt;/strong&gt;: by default, only the main repository is used for installation. Activating that option, you allow the installer to use packages from the other &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.opensuse.org/Package_repositories#Official_Repositories&quot;&gt;official repositories&lt;/a&gt;, including the update repository, which ensures that the system will be installed with the most current packages and you won&amp;#39;t have to manually apply updates after installation; and&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Include Add-on Products from Separate Media&lt;/strong&gt;: activating that option, you can install software from additional repositories (&lt;a href=&quot;https://en.opensuse.org/Package_repositories#Semi_official_repositories&quot;&gt;semiofficial repositories&lt;/a&gt; and/or &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.opensuse.org/Additional_package_repositories&quot;&gt;third-party repositories&lt;/a&gt;). Right now, that may be useful only if you need to install any driver beforehand. Otherwise, you can wait to install any third-party software after the system itself is installed.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Check the first option (&lt;strong&gt;Alt + A&lt;/strong&gt;) and then choose &lt;strong&gt;Next&lt;/strong&gt; (&lt;strong&gt;Alt + N&lt;/strong&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;3) Partitioning&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;div class=&#39;image no-ads-here text-center&#39; itemscope itemtype=&#39;http://schema.org/ImageObject&#39;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#39;/files/2017/01/opensuse-server-12-en.jpg&#39; title=&#39;&#39;&gt;
&lt;img src=&#39;/files/2017/01/opensuse-server-12-en.jpg&#39; alt=&#39;&#39; class=&#39;img-responsive img-thumbnail&#39; itemprop=&#39;contentUrl&#39;&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By default, openSUSE proposes to create three new partitions:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;/&lt;/code&gt; (root), for system files;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;/home&lt;/code&gt;, for personal files of users; and&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.linux.com/news/all-about-linux-swap-space&quot;&gt;swap&lt;/a&gt;, which is used as a supplement for RAM, similar to the &lt;a href=&quot;https://support.microsoft.com/kb/2160852&quot;&gt;page file&lt;/a&gt; in &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.microsoft.com/windows/&quot;&gt;Windows&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;#39;m not going to dive into details about partitioning here, as that would be a subject for an entire (and long) post. If you need more information, I suggest you take a look at the &lt;a href=&quot;https://doc.opensuse.org/documentation/leap/startup/html/book.opensuse.startup/cha.inst.html#sec.i.yast2.inst_mode.partitioning&quot;&gt;openSUSE Leap official documentation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Note that the &lt;code&gt;/home&lt;/code&gt; partition is not always useful on servers. Consider a DHCP server, for instance, probably only the network administrator will have a personal folder. So, as an alternative to the partitioning setup proposed by the openSUSE installer, here I suggest again &amp;quot;a good start&amp;quot; (following those specs):&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;a swap partition of 1GB; and&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;a &lt;code&gt;/&lt;/code&gt; partition with the remaining disk space (9GB).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Some notes about the swap partition:&lt;/strong&gt; some time ago, it was recommended that the swap partition size should be double of the RAM size. Since the Linux kernel 2.4.10, &lt;a href=&quot;https://doc.opensuse.org/documentation/leap/reference/html/book.opensuse.reference/cha.advdisk.html&quot;&gt;that does not apply anymore&lt;/a&gt;. Nowadays, there is a consensus that having a swap partition is a must for both servers and desktops, but there is no consensus about a recommended size. The official openSUSE documentation (&lt;a href=&quot;https://doc.opensuse.org/documentation/leap/reference/html/book.opensuse.reference/cha.advdisk.html&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://doc.opensuse.org/documentation/leap/reference/html/book.opensuse.reference/cha.pmanage.html&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;) recommends creating a swap partition of at least 256MB. If needed, it&amp;#39;s preferable to add more RAM to the system instead of adding more swap space. For hibernation, the swap partition must be at least as big as the RAM, but hibernation is more common on laptops and desktops than on servers. Documentation of other Linux distributions that may help deciding the swap partition size: &lt;a href=&quot;https://help.ubuntu.com/community/SwapFaq&quot;&gt;Ubuntu&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://access.redhat.com/documentation/en-US/Red_Hat_Enterprise_Linux/7/html/Storage_Administration_Guide/ch-swapspace.html&quot;&gt;Red Hat&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let&amp;#39;s see how we can create a new partition setup following my suggestion.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On the &lt;strong&gt;Suggested Partitioning&lt;/strong&gt; screen (see the above picture), choose &lt;strong&gt;Create Partition Setup&lt;/strong&gt; (&lt;strong&gt;Alt + C&lt;/strong&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On the next screen, select &lt;strong&gt;Custom Partitioning&lt;/strong&gt; (&lt;strong&gt;Alt + C&lt;/strong&gt;) and then &lt;strong&gt;Next&lt;/strong&gt; (&lt;strong&gt;Alt + N&lt;/strong&gt;):&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&#39;image no-ads-here text-center&#39; itemscope itemtype=&#39;http://schema.org/ImageObject&#39;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#39;/files/2017/01/opensuse-server-13-en.jpg&#39; title=&#39;&#39;&gt;
&lt;img src=&#39;/files/2017/01/opensuse-server-13-en.jpg&#39; alt=&#39;&#39; class=&#39;img-responsive img-thumbnail&#39; itemprop=&#39;contentUrl&#39;&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The next screen (&lt;strong&gt;Expert Partitioner&lt;/strong&gt;) lists the available hard disks:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&#39;image no-ads-here text-center&#39; itemscope itemtype=&#39;http://schema.org/ImageObject&#39;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#39;/files/2017/01/opensuse-server-14-en.jpg&#39; title=&#39;&#39;&gt;
&lt;img src=&#39;/files/2017/01/opensuse-server-14-en.jpg&#39; alt=&#39;&#39; class=&#39;img-responsive img-thumbnail&#39; itemprop=&#39;contentUrl&#39;&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Select the only disk available and hit &lt;strong&gt;Enter&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The next screen lists the partitions in the selected disk (by now, none).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let&amp;#39;s create a new empty partition table for that disk. Choose &lt;strong&gt;Expert&lt;/strong&gt;, select &lt;strong&gt;Create New Partition Table&lt;/strong&gt; and hit &lt;strong&gt;Enter&lt;/strong&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&#39;image no-ads-here text-center&#39; itemscope itemtype=&#39;http://schema.org/ImageObject&#39;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#39;/files/2017/01/opensuse-server-15-en.jpg&#39; title=&#39;&#39;&gt;
&lt;img src=&#39;/files/2017/01/opensuse-server-15-en.jpg&#39; alt=&#39;&#39; class=&#39;img-responsive img-thumbnail&#39; itemprop=&#39;contentUrl&#39;&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Select &lt;strong&gt;MSDOS&lt;/strong&gt; as the new partition table type and choose &lt;strong&gt;OK&lt;/strong&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&#39;image no-ads-here text-center&#39; itemscope itemtype=&#39;http://schema.org/ImageObject&#39;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#39;/files/2017/01/opensuse-server-16-en.jpg&#39; title=&#39;&#39;&gt;
&lt;img src=&#39;/files/2017/01/opensuse-server-16-en.jpg&#39; alt=&#39;&#39; class=&#39;img-responsive img-thumbnail&#39; itemprop=&#39;contentUrl&#39;&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The partitioner warns about destroying hard disk data:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&#39;image no-ads-here text-center&#39; itemscope itemtype=&#39;http://schema.org/ImageObject&#39;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#39;/files/2017/01/opensuse-server-17-en.jpg&#39; title=&#39;&#39;&gt;
&lt;img src=&#39;/files/2017/01/opensuse-server-17-en.jpg&#39; alt=&#39;&#39; class=&#39;img-responsive img-thumbnail&#39; itemprop=&#39;contentUrl&#39;&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As the disk has not been used yet, we can safely continue choosing &lt;strong&gt;Yes&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now, back to the list of patitions, choose &lt;strong&gt;Add&lt;/strong&gt; to create the first partition, the swap partition of 1GB.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Select &lt;strong&gt;Primary Partition&lt;/strong&gt; as the new partition type and choose &lt;strong&gt;Next&lt;/strong&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&#39;image no-ads-here text-center&#39; itemscope itemtype=&#39;http://schema.org/ImageObject&#39;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#39;/files/2017/01/opensuse-server-18-en.jpg&#39; title=&#39;&#39;&gt;
&lt;img src=&#39;/files/2017/01/opensuse-server-18-en.jpg&#39; alt=&#39;&#39; class=&#39;img-responsive img-thumbnail&#39; itemprop=&#39;contentUrl&#39;&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In &lt;strong&gt;Size&lt;/strong&gt;, type &lt;strong&gt;1GB&lt;/strong&gt;. Then, choose &lt;strong&gt;Next&lt;/strong&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&#39;image no-ads-here text-center&#39; itemscope itemtype=&#39;http://schema.org/ImageObject&#39;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#39;/files/2017/01/opensuse-server-19-en.jpg&#39; title=&#39;&#39;&gt;
&lt;img src=&#39;/files/2017/01/opensuse-server-19-en.jpg&#39; alt=&#39;&#39; class=&#39;img-responsive img-thumbnail&#39; itemprop=&#39;contentUrl&#39;&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In &lt;strong&gt;Role&lt;/strong&gt;, select &lt;strong&gt;Swap&lt;/strong&gt;. Then, choose &lt;strong&gt;Next&lt;/strong&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&#39;image no-ads-here text-center&#39; itemscope itemtype=&#39;http://schema.org/ImageObject&#39;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#39;/files/2017/01/opensuse-server-20-en.jpg&#39; title=&#39;&#39;&gt;
&lt;img src=&#39;/files/2017/01/opensuse-server-20-en.jpg&#39; alt=&#39;&#39; class=&#39;img-responsive img-thumbnail&#39; itemprop=&#39;contentUrl&#39;&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The next screen allows us to configure several options of the new partition. But when it comes to swap, we don&amp;#39;t need to change a thing: the default settings suggested by the installer are satisfying. We can just choose &lt;strong&gt;Finish&lt;/strong&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&#39;image no-ads-here text-center&#39; itemscope itemtype=&#39;http://schema.org/ImageObject&#39;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#39;/files/2017/01/opensuse-server-21-en.jpg&#39; title=&#39;&#39;&gt;
&lt;img src=&#39;/files/2017/01/opensuse-server-21-en.jpg&#39; alt=&#39;&#39; class=&#39;img-responsive img-thumbnail&#39; itemprop=&#39;contentUrl&#39;&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Back to the list of partitions, now we have the swap partition being listed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let&amp;#39;s choose &lt;strong&gt;Add&lt;/strong&gt; once more to create our second partition, the &lt;code&gt;/&lt;/code&gt; partition with the remaining disk space (9GB).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Select &lt;strong&gt;Primary Partition&lt;/strong&gt; as the new partition type and choose &lt;strong&gt;Next&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On the next screen, select &lt;strong&gt;Maximum Size&lt;/strong&gt; and then choose &lt;strong&gt;Next&lt;/strong&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&#39;image no-ads-here text-center&#39; itemscope itemtype=&#39;http://schema.org/ImageObject&#39;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#39;/files/2017/01/opensuse-server-22-en.jpg&#39; title=&#39;&#39;&gt;
&lt;img src=&#39;/files/2017/01/opensuse-server-22-en.jpg&#39; alt=&#39;&#39; class=&#39;img-responsive img-thumbnail&#39; itemprop=&#39;contentUrl&#39;&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In &lt;strong&gt;Role&lt;/strong&gt;, select &lt;strong&gt;Operating System&lt;/strong&gt;. Then, &lt;strong&gt;Next&lt;/strong&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&#39;image no-ads-here text-center&#39; itemscope itemtype=&#39;http://schema.org/ImageObject&#39;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#39;/files/2017/01/opensuse-server-23-en.jpg&#39; title=&#39;&#39;&gt;
&lt;img src=&#39;/files/2017/01/opensuse-server-23-en.jpg&#39; alt=&#39;&#39; class=&#39;img-responsive img-thumbnail&#39; itemprop=&#39;contentUrl&#39;&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In &lt;strong&gt;Formatting Options&lt;/strong&gt;, let&amp;#39;s just change the &lt;strong&gt;File System&lt;/strong&gt; to the more traditional &lt;strong&gt;Ext4&lt;/strong&gt;. Finally, choose &lt;strong&gt;Finish&lt;/strong&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&#39;image no-ads-here text-center&#39; itemscope itemtype=&#39;http://schema.org/ImageObject&#39;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#39;/files/2017/01/opensuse-server-24-en.jpg&#39; title=&#39;&#39;&gt;
&lt;img src=&#39;/files/2017/01/opensuse-server-24-en.jpg&#39; alt=&#39;&#39; class=&#39;img-responsive img-thumbnail&#39; itemprop=&#39;contentUrl&#39;&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Back to the list of patitions, now we have both the partitions created:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&#39;image no-ads-here text-center&#39; itemscope itemtype=&#39;http://schema.org/ImageObject&#39;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#39;/files/2017/01/opensuse-server-25-en.jpg&#39; title=&#39;&#39;&gt;
&lt;img src=&#39;/files/2017/01/opensuse-server-25-en.jpg&#39; alt=&#39;&#39; class=&#39;img-responsive img-thumbnail&#39; itemprop=&#39;contentUrl&#39;&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Choose &lt;strong&gt;Accept&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The &lt;strong&gt;Suggested Partitioning&lt;/strong&gt; screen now shows our custom partitioning:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&#39;image no-ads-here text-center&#39; itemscope itemtype=&#39;http://schema.org/ImageObject&#39;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#39;/files/2017/01/opensuse-server-26-en.jpg&#39; title=&#39;&#39;&gt;
&lt;img src=&#39;/files/2017/01/opensuse-server-26-en.jpg&#39; alt=&#39;&#39; class=&#39;img-responsive img-thumbnail&#39; itemprop=&#39;contentUrl&#39;&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Choose &lt;strong&gt;Next&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;4) Clock and time zone&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;div class=&#39;image no-ads-here text-center&#39; itemscope itemtype=&#39;http://schema.org/ImageObject&#39;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#39;/files/2017/01/opensuse-server-27-en.jpg&#39; title=&#39;&#39;&gt;
&lt;img src=&#39;/files/2017/01/opensuse-server-27-en.jpg&#39; alt=&#39;&#39; class=&#39;img-responsive img-thumbnail&#39; itemprop=&#39;contentUrl&#39;&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Check that your time zone, date and time settings are correct.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you need to change the time zone, first select a &lt;strong&gt;Region&lt;/strong&gt; (e.g. &lt;strong&gt;Brazil&lt;/strong&gt;), then select a &lt;strong&gt;Time Zone&lt;/strong&gt; (e.g. &lt;strong&gt;São Paulo&lt;/strong&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As your server is going to run Linux only, keep the &lt;strong&gt;Hardware Clock Set to UTC&lt;/strong&gt; option checked (it is already checked by default). If you need further information about that option, please refer to the &lt;a href=&quot;https://doc.opensuse.org/documentation/leap/startup/html/book.opensuse.startup/cha.inst.html#sec.i.yast2.timezone&quot;&gt;openSUSE Leap official documentation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When you finish, choose &lt;strong&gt;Next&lt;/strong&gt; (&lt;strong&gt;Alt + N&lt;/strong&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;5) Online repositories&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have selected the &lt;strong&gt;Add Online Repositories Before Installation&lt;/strong&gt; option earlier, the &lt;strong&gt;List of Online Repositories&lt;/strong&gt; screen lets you choose which official openSUSE Leap online repositories will be used during installation:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&#39;image no-ads-here text-center&#39; itemscope itemtype=&#39;http://schema.org/ImageObject&#39;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#39;/files/2017/01/opensuse-server-28-en.jpg&#39; title=&#39;&#39;&gt;
&lt;img src=&#39;/files/2017/01/opensuse-server-28-en.jpg&#39; alt=&#39;&#39; class=&#39;img-responsive img-thumbnail&#39; itemprop=&#39;contentUrl&#39;&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Enable only the following repositories:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Main Repository (OSS)&lt;/strong&gt;: the main openSUSE Leap repository, contains &lt;a href=&quot;https://opensource.org/osd-annotated&quot;&gt;open source software&lt;/a&gt; only; and&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Main Update Repository&lt;/strong&gt;: contains official updates for OSS packages.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To enable or disable a repository on that list, select the desired repository using the &lt;strong&gt;up and down arrow&lt;/strong&gt; keys and press the &lt;strong&gt;spacebar&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When you finish, choose &lt;strong&gt;Next&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;6) Desktop selection&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;div class=&#39;image no-ads-here text-center&#39; itemscope itemtype=&#39;http://schema.org/ImageObject&#39;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#39;/files/2017/01/opensuse-server-29-en.jpg&#39; title=&#39;&#39;&gt;
&lt;img src=&#39;/files/2017/01/opensuse-server-29-en.jpg&#39; alt=&#39;&#39; class=&#39;img-responsive img-thumbnail&#39; itemprop=&#39;contentUrl&#39;&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On that screen, the installer offers some of the desktop environments available for openSUSE. Since graphical interfaces are not really common on servers (it makes more sense to use applications such as &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.libreoffice.org/&quot;&gt;LibreOffice&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.mozilla.org/en-US/firefox/&quot;&gt;Mozilla Firefox&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.kde.org/applications/games/kmines/&quot;&gt;KMines&lt;/a&gt; on desktops), let&amp;#39;s choose &lt;strong&gt;Server (Text Mode)&lt;/strong&gt; with &lt;strong&gt;Alt + S&lt;/strong&gt; and then &lt;strong&gt;Next&lt;/strong&gt; with &lt;strong&gt;Alt + N&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;7) Username and password&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;div class=&#39;image no-ads-here text-center&#39; itemscope itemtype=&#39;http://schema.org/ImageObject&#39;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#39;/files/2017/01/opensuse-server-30-en.jpg&#39; title=&#39;&#39;&gt;
&lt;img src=&#39;/files/2017/01/opensuse-server-30-en.jpg&#39; alt=&#39;&#39; class=&#39;img-responsive img-thumbnail&#39; itemprop=&#39;contentUrl&#39;&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On that screen, you are going to create an user account for you to access the server. Enter your full name and the desired username and password.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Note that the installer suggests to:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;use the same password for the administrator user (in Linux, it is called superuser or &lt;em&gt;root&lt;/em&gt;); and&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;automatically log in your user account when the server turns on.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Those options are suggested for convenience, but actually they make your system a little less secure. As we are setting up a server and security is a concern, uncheck both the &lt;strong&gt;Use this password for system administrator&lt;/strong&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;Automatic Login&lt;/strong&gt; options, so that an username and password must be provided to access the server.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When you finish, choose &lt;strong&gt;Next&lt;/strong&gt; (&lt;strong&gt;Alt + N&lt;/strong&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The installer may complain about your password if it is considered easy to guess:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&#39;image no-ads-here text-center&#39; itemscope itemtype=&#39;http://schema.org/ImageObject&#39;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#39;/files/2017/01/opensuse-server-31-en.jpg&#39; title=&#39;&#39;&gt;
&lt;img src=&#39;/files/2017/01/opensuse-server-31-en.jpg&#39; alt=&#39;&#39; class=&#39;img-responsive img-thumbnail&#39; itemprop=&#39;contentUrl&#39;&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If that is the case, it is strongly recommended that you choose &lt;strong&gt;No&lt;/strong&gt; and set up a safer password.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you need help on how to elaborate a strong password, you may check this Lifehacker&amp;#39;s post &lt;a href=&quot;http://lifehacker.com/four-methods-to-create-a-secure-password-youll-actually-1601854240&quot;&gt;Four Methods to Create a Secure Password You&amp;#39;ll Actually Remember&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On the next screen, as you have unchecked the &lt;strong&gt;Use this password for system administrator&lt;/strong&gt; option, you are asked to enter a password for the root user:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&#39;image no-ads-here text-center&#39; itemscope itemtype=&#39;http://schema.org/ImageObject&#39;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#39;/files/2017/01/opensuse-server-32-en.jpg&#39; title=&#39;&#39;&gt;
&lt;img src=&#39;/files/2017/01/opensuse-server-32-en.jpg&#39; alt=&#39;&#39; class=&#39;img-responsive img-thumbnail&#39; itemprop=&#39;contentUrl&#39;&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When you finish, choose &lt;strong&gt;Next&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;8) Installation overview&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;div class=&#39;image no-ads-here text-center&#39; itemscope itemtype=&#39;http://schema.org/ImageObject&#39;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#39;/files/2017/01/opensuse-server-33-en.jpg&#39; title=&#39;&#39;&gt;
&lt;img src=&#39;/files/2017/01/opensuse-server-33-en.jpg&#39; alt=&#39;&#39; class=&#39;img-responsive img-thumbnail&#39; itemprop=&#39;contentUrl&#39;&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On the last screen before the real installation takes place, you can review the installation settings. Check that everything is as desired. Use the &lt;strong&gt;up and down arrow&lt;/strong&gt; keys to inspect the overview. Once you choose &lt;strong&gt;Install&lt;/strong&gt;, there will be no way back.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you need to change any setting, select the respective headline using the &lt;strong&gt;up and down arrow&lt;/strong&gt; keys and hit &lt;strong&gt;Enter&lt;/strong&gt; to go to the corresponding screen.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Please observe that by default both the firewall and remote access via the secure shell (SSH) are disabled:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&#39;image no-ads-here text-center&#39; itemscope itemtype=&#39;http://schema.org/ImageObject&#39;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#39;/files/2017/01/opensuse-server-34-en.jpg&#39; title=&#39;&#39;&gt;
&lt;img src=&#39;/files/2017/01/opensuse-server-34-en.jpg&#39; alt=&#39;&#39; class=&#39;img-responsive img-thumbnail&#39; itemprop=&#39;contentUrl&#39;&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Select &lt;strong&gt;enable&lt;/strong&gt; and hit &lt;strong&gt;Enter&lt;/strong&gt; to turn the firewall on. Do that for SSH too:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&#39;image no-ads-here text-center&#39; itemscope itemtype=&#39;http://schema.org/ImageObject&#39;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#39;/files/2017/01/opensuse-server-35-en.jpg&#39; title=&#39;&#39;&gt;
&lt;img src=&#39;/files/2017/01/opensuse-server-35-en.jpg&#39; alt=&#39;&#39; class=&#39;img-responsive img-thumbnail&#39; itemprop=&#39;contentUrl&#39;&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If there is nothing else to change, choose &lt;strong&gt;Install&lt;/strong&gt; (&lt;strong&gt;Alt + I&lt;/strong&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A confirmation message is shown:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&#39;image no-ads-here text-center&#39; itemscope itemtype=&#39;http://schema.org/ImageObject&#39;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#39;/files/2017/01/opensuse-server-36-en.jpg&#39; title=&#39;&#39;&gt;
&lt;img src=&#39;/files/2017/01/opensuse-server-36-en.jpg&#39; alt=&#39;&#39; class=&#39;img-responsive img-thumbnail&#39; itemprop=&#39;contentUrl&#39;&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Choose &lt;strong&gt;Install&lt;/strong&gt; (&lt;strong&gt;Alt + I&lt;/strong&gt;) to start &lt;em&gt;de facto&lt;/em&gt; installing openSUSE Leap.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;9) Actual installation&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;div class=&#39;image no-ads-here text-center&#39; itemscope itemtype=&#39;http://schema.org/ImageObject&#39;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#39;/files/2017/01/opensuse-server-37-en.jpg&#39; title=&#39;&#39;&gt;
&lt;img src=&#39;/files/2017/01/opensuse-server-37-en.jpg&#39; alt=&#39;&#39; class=&#39;img-responsive img-thumbnail&#39; itemprop=&#39;contentUrl&#39;&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now the actual installation is performed. That screen shows its progress in detail.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Please note that, since packages are downloaded from the Internet, the installation may take longer or may be faster depending on the speed of your connection.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When the installation is done, the installer asks you to reboot the server:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&#39;image no-ads-here text-center&#39; itemscope itemtype=&#39;http://schema.org/ImageObject&#39;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#39;/files/2017/01/opensuse-server-38-en.jpg&#39; title=&#39;&#39;&gt;
&lt;img src=&#39;/files/2017/01/opensuse-server-38-en.jpg&#39; alt=&#39;&#39; class=&#39;img-responsive img-thumbnail&#39; itemprop=&#39;contentUrl&#39;&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You just need to hit &lt;strong&gt;Enter&lt;/strong&gt; or wait for the server to restart by itself.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While the server is restarted, you can remove the openSUSE installation medium, it is no longer needed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Server installed&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;div class=&#39;image no-ads-here text-center&#39; itemscope itemtype=&#39;http://schema.org/ImageObject&#39;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#39;/files/2017/01/opensuse-server-39.jpg&#39; title=&#39;&#39;&gt;
&lt;img src=&#39;/files/2017/01/opensuse-server-39.jpg&#39; alt=&#39;&#39; class=&#39;img-responsive img-thumbnail&#39; itemprop=&#39;contentUrl&#39;&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Installation is now complete. The operating system is already on the hard disk. But there are still a few basic settings that need to be adjusted before the server can be actually considered ready to use.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As I realized that this post is already very long, I decided to split it into two parts. I left some details for the next post.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Follow the Linux Kamarada Project to read the second part as soon as it&amp;#39;s published!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
                <pubDate>Wed, 25 Jan 2017 06:20:00 -0200</pubDate>
                <link>https://kamarada.github.io/en/2017/01/25/how-to-install-opensuse-leap-linux-on-a-server/</link>
                <guid isPermaLink="true">https://kamarada.github.io/en/2017/01/25/how-to-install-opensuse-leap-linux-on-a-server/</guid>
                
                
                    <category>en</category>
                
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>Optimal Release for Linux Professionals Arrives with openSUSE Leap 42.2</title>
                <description>&lt;h2&gt;A Professional Distribution for Developers, System Administrators and Users&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Members of the openSUSE Project are pleased to announce the release of the next minor version of Leap; openSUSE Leap 42.2! Leap is made to give stability-minded users and conservative technology adopters peace of mind. openSUSE Leap 42.2 is powered by the Linux 4.4 Long-Term-Support (LTS) kernel and is a secure, stable and reliable server operating system for deploying IT services in physical, virtual or cloud environments.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A selective process of including well-established packages in openSUSE Leap 42.2 gives new meaning to the term &lt;em&gt;Linux Optimization&lt;/em&gt;; openSUSE Leap is simply the safe choice that offers Linux professionals a user-friendly desktop and a feature-rich server environment.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&#39;image no-ads-here text-center&#39; itemscope itemtype=&#39;http://schema.org/ImageObject&#39;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#39;/files/2015/11/Leap-green.png&#39; title=&#39;&#39;&gt;
&lt;img src=&#39;/files/2015/11/Leap-green.png&#39; alt=&#39;&#39; class=&#39;img-responsive img-thumbnail&#39; itemprop=&#39;contentUrl&#39; style=&quot;max-width: 150px;&quot;&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Continuing the tradition of using source code from &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.suse.com/products/server&quot;&gt;SUSE Linux Enterprise&lt;/a&gt; (SLE), openSUSE Leap 42.2 provides a level of stability unmatched by other Linux distributions. With community-built packages on top of Leap&amp;#39;s enterprise reliability, openSUSE Leap users benefit both from community and enterprise maintenance efforts.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote class=&quot;twitter-tweet&quot; data-lang=&quot;pt&quot;&gt;&lt;p lang=&quot;en&quot; dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;Wow! &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/openSUSE&quot;&gt;@openSUSE&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/SUSE&quot;&gt;@SUSE&lt;/a&gt; together creating great distros for devs and operators! Check out openSUSE Leap 42.2: &lt;a href=&quot;https://t.co/jEeQFltLe5&quot;&gt;https://t.co/jEeQFltLe5&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&amp;mdash; Michael Miller (@michaelwmiller) &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/michaelwmiller/status/798551355795206144&quot;&gt;15 de novembro de 2016&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;script async src=&quot;//platform.twitter.com/widgets.js&quot; charset=&quot;utf-8&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Contributions to openSUSE Leap from SUSE include several new features like Network Functions Virtualization capabilities that combines &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.openvswitch.org/&quot;&gt;Open vSwitch&lt;/a&gt; with the Data Plane Development Kit to process packets faster. YaST also has a significant amount of improvements and new features.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Community contributions were equally enormous as more than 1,400 new packages made it into this newest Leap version, with 42.2 providing 17% more packages than 42.1.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of those community packages includes &lt;a href=&quot;http://health.gnu.org/&quot;&gt;GNU Health&lt;/a&gt; Version 3.0.4. This Free Health and Hospital Information System is used by hospitals, governments and institutions under a free license. GNU Health allows management and analysis of a huge amount of data and aspects.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Another new package in Leap 42.2 is &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.prelude-siem.org/&quot;&gt;Prelude Security Information &amp;amp; Event Management (SIEM)&lt;/a&gt; system, which collects, normalizes, sorts, aggregates, correlates and reports all security-related events (IDMEF).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A large community effort and cooperation between openSUSE and KDE has brought a Long-Term Support version for &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.kde.org/announcements/plasma-5.8.2.php&quot;&gt;Plasma 5.8&lt;/a&gt;, which improves multiple monitor support out-of-the-box.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote class=&quot;twitter-tweet&quot; data-lang=&quot;pt&quot;&gt;&lt;p lang=&quot;en&quot; dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;Tons of great feedback from devs &amp;amp; ops about using &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/openSUSE&quot;&gt;@openSUSE&lt;/a&gt; Leap (42.2 on its way in a few hours!) for dev &amp;amp; then move to &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/SUSE&quot;&gt;@SUSE&lt;/a&gt; production!&lt;/p&gt;&amp;mdash; Thomas Di Giacomo (@thomasdigiacomo) &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/thomasdigiacomo/status/798547292143828992&quot;&gt;15 de novembro de 2016&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;script async src=&quot;//platform.twitter.com/widgets.js&quot; charset=&quot;utf-8&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Leap provides an ideal &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=eVXDGnaYbKQ&quot;&gt;dev-to-production&lt;/a&gt; model with SLE for developers and system administrators who want to align their development and production environments. openSUSE Leap is highly stable and is a safe choice for sysadmins, developers and desktop users.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The newest Leap version improves user capabilities with &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.opensuse.org/Portal:Snapper&quot;&gt;snapper&lt;/a&gt; snapshots that are based on the Btrfs filesystem. A new Btrfs concept for quota makes snapper much less disk-hungry. It is configured by default on fresh installations and can be &lt;a href=&quot;http://snapper.io/2016/05/18/space-aware-cleanup.html&quot;&gt;manually setup&lt;/a&gt; after upgrading to Leap 42.2. &lt;a href=&quot;http://snapper.io/&quot;&gt;Snapper&lt;/a&gt; is a &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Poka-yoke&quot;&gt;poka-yoke&lt;/a&gt; and can give system administrators confidence about updating new packages and rolling back the system if any errors occur.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Leap also offers users, developers and system administrators an easy path to move to other operating systems like openSUSE&amp;#39;s faster, more updated distribution &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.opensuse.org/Tumbleweed&quot;&gt;Tumbleweed&lt;/a&gt;, with the newest upstream packages and software versions provided on a rolling release basis, or to an enterprise-level support system with &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.suse.com/products/server&quot;&gt;SLE&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;See for yourself why openSUSE Leap is an acclaimed community-enterprise distribution.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;openSUSE Leap 42.2 is…&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;div class=&#39;row&#39;&gt;
&lt;div class=&#39;col-sm-2&#39;&gt;
&lt;div class=&#39;image no-ads-here text-center&#39; itemscope itemtype=&#39;http://schema.org/ImageObject&#39;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#39;/assets/icons/oxygen/48x48/status/meeting-participant.png&#39; title=&#39;&#39;&gt;
&lt;img src=&#39;/assets/icons/oxygen/48x48/status/meeting-participant.png&#39; alt=&#39;&#39; class=&#39;img-responsive img-thumbnail&#39; itemprop=&#39;contentUrl&#39;&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&#39;col-sm-10&#39;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;more-enterprise&quot;&gt;More Enterprise&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That’s right. After basing openSUSE Leap 42.1 on SLE (SUSE Linux Enterprise), Leap 42.2 gets even more source code from the release of &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.suse.com/promo/sle/&quot;&gt;SLE 12&lt;/a&gt; Service Pack 2. New technologies such as NVDIMM, OmniPATH, Data Plane Development Kit with openVSwitch are back ported for the release. XEN no longer requires it’s own kernel and is supported by the default kernel. Along with the shared SLE codebase, openSUSE Leap 42.2 gets packages, maintenance and bug fixes from the openSUSE community and SUSE engineers. The 42 series of Leap achieves at a minimum 36 months of maintenance and security updates starting from 42.1.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&#39;row&#39;&gt;
&lt;div class=&#39;col-sm-2&#39;&gt;
&lt;div class=&#39;image no-ads-here text-center&#39; itemscope itemtype=&#39;http://schema.org/ImageObject&#39;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#39;/assets/icons/oxygen/48x48/places/network-server.png&#39; title=&#39;&#39;&gt;
&lt;img src=&#39;/assets/icons/oxygen/48x48/places/network-server.png&#39; alt=&#39;&#39; class=&#39;img-responsive img-thumbnail&#39; itemprop=&#39;contentUrl&#39;&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&#39;col-sm-10&#39;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;server-ready&quot;&gt;Server Ready&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;openSUSE Leap 42.2 is the first Leap release to offer a Server profile as clear option during the installation. With no graphical environment, a Server install of Leap stands ready to do whatever you need from it. Something as simple as running a Web or Mail platform is easier than ever, as are complex projects using virtualization or container technologies.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s also good to remember that Leap and all other openSUSE and SLE distributions have support for a &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.opensuse.org/SDB:Installation_with_little_memory#Text_mode&quot;&gt;full-featured textmode installer&lt;/a&gt;, giving all the same functionality as the graphical installer without the need for X. Our installer is also fully capable of doing &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.opensuse.org/SDB:Remote_installation&quot;&gt;installations remotely using VNC or SSH&lt;/a&gt;, letting you set up your openSUSE Leap server without needing to be anywhere near it at all.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&#39;row&#39;&gt;
&lt;div class=&#39;col-sm-12&#39;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;the-return-of-the-konqi&quot;&gt;The Return of the Konqi&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;image no-ads-here text-center&quot; itemscope=&quot;&quot; itemtype=&quot;http://schema.org/ImageObject&quot;&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;/files/2016/11/konqi.png&quot; title=&quot;&quot;&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/files/2016/11/konqi.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;img-responsive img-thumbnail&quot; itemprop=&quot;contentUrl&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Konqi has returned and is in full force. Plasma 5.8 brings a whole new component to openSUSE Leap. As the first Long Term Supported release for Plasma, Plasma 5.8 complements stability-minded Leap users. In unison with &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.qt.io/qt5-6/&quot;&gt;Qt 5.6&lt;/a&gt; and Frameworks 5.26, Plasma 5.8 will bring Leap 42.2 users excellent KDE reliability and stability.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&#39;row&#39;&gt;
&lt;div class=&#39;col-sm-2&#39;&gt;
&lt;div class=&#39;image no-ads-here text-center&#39; itemscope itemtype=&#39;http://schema.org/ImageObject&#39;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#39;/assets/icons/oxygen/48x48/places/start-here-branding.png&#39; title=&#39;&#39;&gt;
&lt;img src=&#39;/assets/icons/oxygen/48x48/places/start-here-branding.png&#39; alt=&#39;&#39; class=&#39;img-responsive img-thumbnail&#39; itemprop=&#39;contentUrl&#39;&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&#39;col-sm-10&#39;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;the-kernel&quot;&gt;The Kernel&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The 4.4 LTS Linux Kernel for openSUSE Leap 42.2 improves file system performance and features, including a new balance filter for Btrfs. The default kernel now has paravirtualization enabled. The kernel version also improves cryptography and security support for Trusted Platform Module 2.0 chips as well as adds support for nested Virtualization through KVM. Networking is dramatically improved for IP Virtual Server and IPv6 and of course there is more updates and changes for the multiple architectures.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Get Leap!&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Downloads of openSUSE Leap 42.2 can be found at &lt;a href=&quot;http://software.opensuse.org/&quot;&gt;software.opensuse.org&lt;/a&gt;. We recommend checking out the &lt;a href=&quot;https://doc.opensuse.org/release-notes/x86_64/openSUSE/Leap/42.2/&quot;&gt;Release Notes&lt;/a&gt; before upgrade or installation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Users currently running &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.opensuse.org/Portal:42.1&quot;&gt;openSUSE Leap 42.1&lt;/a&gt; can &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.opensuse.org/Upgrade&quot;&gt;upgrade to openSUSE Leap 42.2 via the instructions at this link&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The AArch64 architecture port has continued to mature and is now considered stable. ARMv7 has successfully entered the Leap sphere and is available now as well, giving users an upgrade path for their 13.2 installations. To find instructions on how to install openSUSE Leap on a given ARM system, please visit &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.opensuse.org/Portal:ARM&quot;&gt;the ARM wiki&lt;/a&gt; for more information.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Thanks!&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;openSUSE Leap 42.2 represents the combined effort of thousands of developers who participate in our distributions and projects shipped with it. The contributors, inside and outside the openSUSE Project, should be proud of this release, and they deserve a major &lt;strong&gt;&amp;quot;thank you&amp;quot;&lt;/strong&gt; for all of the hard work and care that have gone into it. We believe Leap is the ideal Linux distribution for developers, sysadmins and users. We hope you have a lot of fun using it, and we look forward to working with you on the next release or in &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.opensuse.org/Tumbleweed&quot;&gt;Tumbleweed&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;For Developers&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;div class=&#39;row&#39;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#39;col-sm-4&#39;&gt;&lt;div class=&#39;image no-ads-here text-center&#39; itemscope itemtype=&#39;http://schema.org/ImageObject&#39;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#39;/files/2016/11/Kde_qt5_designer.jpg&#39; title=&#39;KDE Qt5 designer&#39;&gt;
&lt;img src=&#39;/files/2016/11/Kde_qt5_designer.jpg&#39; alt=&#39;KDE Qt5 designer&#39; class=&#39;img-responsive img-thumbnail&#39; itemprop=&#39;contentUrl&#39;&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;

&lt;em class=&#39;caption&#39; itemprop=&#39;description&#39;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;KDE Qt5 designer&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;/em&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#39;col-sm-4&#39;&gt;&lt;div class=&#39;image no-ads-here text-center&#39; itemscope itemtype=&#39;http://schema.org/ImageObject&#39;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#39;/files/2016/11/GNOME_Builder_42.2.jpg&#39; title=&#39;GNOME Builder&#39;&gt;
&lt;img src=&#39;/files/2016/11/GNOME_Builder_42.2.jpg&#39; alt=&#39;GNOME Builder&#39; class=&#39;img-responsive img-thumbnail&#39; itemprop=&#39;contentUrl&#39;&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em class=&#39;caption&#39; itemprop=&#39;description&#39;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;GNOME Builder&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#39;col-sm-4&#39;&gt;&lt;div class=&#39;image no-ads-here text-center&#39; itemscope itemtype=&#39;http://schema.org/ImageObject&#39;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#39;/files/2016/11/Anjuta_42.2.jpg&#39; title=&#39;KDE Anjunta&#39;&gt;
&lt;img src=&#39;/files/2016/11/Anjuta_42.2.jpg&#39; alt=&#39;KDE Anjunta&#39; class=&#39;img-responsive img-thumbnail&#39; itemprop=&#39;contentUrl&#39;&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em class=&#39;caption&#39; itemprop=&#39;description&#39;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;KDE Anjunta&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&#39;row&#39;&gt;
&lt;div class=&#39;col-sm-2&#39;&gt;
&lt;div class=&#39;image no-ads-here text-center&#39; itemscope itemtype=&#39;http://schema.org/ImageObject&#39;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#39;/assets/icons/hicolor/48x48/apps/yast-network.png&#39; title=&#39;&#39;&gt;
&lt;img src=&#39;/assets/icons/hicolor/48x48/apps/yast-network.png&#39; alt=&#39;&#39; class=&#39;img-responsive img-thumbnail&#39; itemprop=&#39;contentUrl&#39;&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&#39;col-sm-10&#39;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;containers&quot;&gt;Containers&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;openSUSE Leap 42.2 is ships with &lt;a href=&quot;https://blog.docker.com/2016/06/docker-1-12-built-in-orchestration/&quot;&gt;Docker 1.12&lt;/a&gt; which builds upon Dockers &lt;a href=&quot;https://blog.docker.com/2016/04/docker-engine-1-11-runc/&quot;&gt;recent adoption of runC and containerd&lt;/a&gt; to bring the latest orchestration features, such as Docker Swarm.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&#39;row&#39;&gt;
&lt;div class=&#39;col-sm-2&#39;&gt;
&lt;div class=&#39;image no-ads-here text-center&#39; itemscope itemtype=&#39;http://schema.org/ImageObject&#39;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#39;/assets/icons/oxygen/48x48/categories/applications-development.png&#39; title=&#39;&#39;&gt;
&lt;img src=&#39;/assets/icons/oxygen/48x48/categories/applications-development.png&#39; alt=&#39;&#39; class=&#39;img-responsive img-thumbnail&#39; itemprop=&#39;contentUrl&#39;&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&#39;col-sm-10&#39;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;ides-and-tooling&quot;&gt;IDEs and tooling&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Leap 42.2 carries a mature, LTS version of the Qt 5 GUI toolkit (5.6). With more than 800 improvements from the previous version in Leap 42.1, Qt 5.6 also brings some non-critical security fixes in the Qt framework and in third-party libraries.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;gtk 3.20, shared with SUSE Linux Enterprise 12 SP2, provides a solid &amp;amp; stable toolkit for building gtk based applications. GNOME Builder is offered as a powerful general purpose IDE for not only gtk applications based on C, C++ and Vala, but many other languages in addition.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For all your compiling needs Leap 42.2 contains gcc 4.8.5, 5.3.1 and 6.1.1. llvm-clang is also available at version 3.8.0. Leap also includes CMake 3.5 providing a powerful, cross-platform build environment for open-source project developers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The OpenSSL toolkit found in Leap 42.2 is 1.0.2h, which modifies behavior of ALPN and prevents ASN.1 BIO from excessive memory allocation. OpenSSH is version 7.2p2 in this latest stable release and sanitizes X11 authentication credentials.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&#39;row&#39;&gt;
&lt;div class=&#39;col-sm-2&#39;&gt;
&lt;div class=&#39;image no-ads-here text-center&#39; itemscope itemtype=&#39;http://schema.org/ImageObject&#39;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#39;/assets/icons/oxygen/48x48/categories/applications-engineering.png&#39; title=&#39;&#39;&gt;
&lt;img src=&#39;/assets/icons/oxygen/48x48/categories/applications-engineering.png&#39; alt=&#39;&#39; class=&#39;img-responsive img-thumbnail&#39; itemprop=&#39;contentUrl&#39;&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&#39;col-sm-10&#39;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;languages-and-libraries&quot;&gt;Languages and Libraries&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Programming languages found in openSUSE Leap 42.2 include Python 2.7, Ruby 2.1 and Perl 5.18. This Leap release provides new major version libraries for libvirt (2.0) and libzypp (16.2). Leap also has the well established glibc 2.22 and libsigc++ 2.8, which defines signals and connects them to any callback function, whether static or virtual.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;For Sysadmins&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;div class=&#39;row&#39;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#39;col-sm-4&#39;&gt;&lt;div class=&#39;image no-ads-here text-center&#39; itemscope itemtype=&#39;http://schema.org/ImageObject&#39;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#39;/files/2016/11/Installation_overview_42.2.jpg&#39; title=&#39;Installation overview&#39;&gt;
&lt;img src=&#39;/files/2016/11/Installation_overview_42.2.jpg&#39; alt=&#39;Installation overview&#39; class=&#39;img-responsive img-thumbnail&#39; itemprop=&#39;contentUrl&#39;&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;

&lt;em class=&#39;caption&#39; itemprop=&#39;description&#39;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Installation overview&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;/em&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#39;col-sm-4&#39;&gt;&lt;div class=&#39;image no-ads-here text-center&#39; itemscope itemtype=&#39;http://schema.org/ImageObject&#39;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#39;/files/2016/11/GNOME_YaST_42.2.jpg&#39; title=&#39;YaST&#39;&gt;
&lt;img src=&#39;/files/2016/11/GNOME_YaST_42.2.jpg&#39; alt=&#39;YaST&#39; class=&#39;img-responsive img-thumbnail&#39; itemprop=&#39;contentUrl&#39;&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em class=&#39;caption&#39; itemprop=&#39;description&#39;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;YaST&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#39;col-sm-4&#39;&gt;&lt;div class=&#39;image no-ads-here text-center&#39; itemscope itemtype=&#39;http://schema.org/ImageObject&#39;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#39;/files/2016/11/Gnome-control-center.jpg&#39; title=&#39;Control Center 42.2&#39;&gt;
&lt;img src=&#39;/files/2016/11/Gnome-control-center.jpg&#39; alt=&#39;Control Center 42.2&#39; class=&#39;img-responsive img-thumbnail&#39; itemprop=&#39;contentUrl&#39;&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em class=&#39;caption&#39; itemprop=&#39;description&#39;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Control Center 42.2&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&#39;row&#39;&gt;
&lt;div class=&#39;col-sm-2&#39;&gt;
&lt;div class=&#39;image no-ads-here text-center&#39; itemscope itemtype=&#39;http://schema.org/ImageObject&#39;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#39;/assets/icons/hicolor/64x64/apps/yast-virtualisation.png&#39; title=&#39;&#39;&gt;
&lt;img src=&#39;/assets/icons/hicolor/64x64/apps/yast-virtualisation.png&#39; alt=&#39;&#39; class=&#39;img-responsive img-thumbnail&#39; itemprop=&#39;contentUrl&#39;&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&#39;col-sm-10&#39;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;virtualization&quot;&gt;Virtualization&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;openSUSE Leap 42.2 is full of virtualization solutions. QEMU 2.6.1 and VirtualBox 5.0.24 make openSUSE Leap 42.2 a perfect base system to distribute applications. Set up is easy with YaST and gnome-boxes, so you’ll be able deploy solutions quickly and easily. openSUSE Leap 42.2 has Xen and KVM. It also supports Linux containers in the form of both Docker and LXC.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&#39;row&#39;&gt;
&lt;div class=&#39;col-sm-2&#39;&gt;
&lt;div class=&#39;image no-ads-here text-center&#39; itemscope itemtype=&#39;http://schema.org/ImageObject&#39;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#39;/assets/icons/hicolor/48x48/apps/yast.png&#39; title=&#39;&#39;&gt;
&lt;img src=&#39;/assets/icons/hicolor/48x48/apps/yast.png&#39; alt=&#39;&#39; class=&#39;img-responsive img-thumbnail&#39; itemprop=&#39;contentUrl&#39;&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&#39;col-sm-10&#39;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;yast-goodness&quot;&gt;YaST Goodness&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;YaST Sprints leading up to the release of openSUSE Leap 42.2 have brought tons of goodness and are making YaST more intuitive than ever. The YaST community revamped the user interface to improve usability and continues adding new tools and modules that have been in Tumbleweed for some time and are now been added to the Leap family.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;yast2-alternatives is a new module to manage openSUSE’s alternatives system developed during Google Summer of Code 2016. Another module, yast2-vpn, is a module for configuring VPN gateway and clients. yast2-auth-client is another module to configure centralized system authentication and it has been almost completely rewritten. New features to YaST have improved bootloader management, which offers support for Trusted Boot and has a revamped configuration of password protection. yast2-firewall now includes full support for firewalld, in addition to the already existing SuSEFirewall2.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When something goes wrong during installation, the system now offers the possibility of starting a debugger; users with Ruby knowledge can use it to check what went wrong or even to work around the problem. There have also been several enhancements, including installer memory usage being significantly reduced. The selection and configuration of keyboard layouts and console fonts has also been adapted for better compatibility with systemd. There are several other YaST improvements that can be found on the &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.opensuse.org/Archive:Features_42.2#YaST&quot;&gt;features page&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&#39;row&#39;&gt;
&lt;div class=&#39;col-sm-2&#39;&gt;
&lt;div class=&#39;image no-ads-here text-center&#39; itemscope itemtype=&#39;http://schema.org/ImageObject&#39;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#39;/assets/icons/oxygen/48x48/apps/krdc.png&#39; title=&#39;&#39;&gt;
&lt;img src=&#39;/assets/icons/oxygen/48x48/apps/krdc.png&#39; alt=&#39;&#39; class=&#39;img-responsive img-thumbnail&#39; itemprop=&#39;contentUrl&#39;&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&#39;col-sm-10&#39;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;managing-systems&quot;&gt;Managing Systems&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;openSUSE Leap has Samba 4.4.2, which has improved support for working against a Windows 2003 domain. systemd 228 creates a plain directory instead of a subvolume (even on a Btrfs file system) if the root directory is a plain directory, and not a subvolume, which should simplify things with certain chroot() environments which are not aware of the concept of btrfs subvolumes. AppStream version in Leap enhances the interaction of software repositories. MariaDB remains the same version as it was in the previous release and MySQL’s small upgrade to version 5.1.35 resolves a number of issues including a failover being triggered inadvertently and a failover process that kept trying to connect to an unavailable server.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It is also worth remembering that openSUSE Leap uses Delta RPMs for all &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.opensuse.org/Portal:Maintenance&quot;&gt;maintenance updates&lt;/a&gt;, ensuring that the long term bandwidth requirements for maintaining your Leap system are as small as possible.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;For Users&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;div class=&#39;row&#39;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#39;col-sm-3&#39;&gt;&lt;div class=&#39;image no-ads-here text-center&#39; itemscope itemtype=&#39;http://schema.org/ImageObject&#39;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#39;/files/2016/11/LibreOffice_in_GNOME_Leap_42.2.jpg&#39; title=&#39;LibreOffice 5 in GNOME 3.20&#39;&gt;
&lt;img src=&#39;/files/2016/11/LibreOffice_in_GNOME_Leap_42.2.jpg&#39; alt=&#39;LibreOffice 5 in GNOME 3.20&#39; class=&#39;img-responsive img-thumbnail&#39; itemprop=&#39;contentUrl&#39;&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;

&lt;em class=&#39;caption&#39; itemprop=&#39;description&#39;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;LibreOffice 5 in GNOME 3.20&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;/em&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#39;col-sm-3&#39;&gt;&lt;div class=&#39;image no-ads-here text-center&#39; itemscope itemtype=&#39;http://schema.org/ImageObject&#39;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#39;/files/2016/11/KDE_Gimp_Leap_42.2.jpg&#39; title=&#39;GIMP in Plasma 5.8&#39;&gt;
&lt;img src=&#39;/files/2016/11/KDE_Gimp_Leap_42.2.jpg&#39; alt=&#39;GIMP in Plasma 5.8&#39; class=&#39;img-responsive img-thumbnail&#39; itemprop=&#39;contentUrl&#39;&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em class=&#39;caption&#39; itemprop=&#39;description&#39;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;GIMP in Plasma 5.8&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#39;col-sm-3&#39;&gt;&lt;div class=&#39;image no-ads-here text-center&#39; itemscope itemtype=&#39;http://schema.org/ImageObject&#39;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#39;/files/2016/11/VLC_in_GNOME_Leap_42.2.jpg&#39; title=&#39;VLC in GNOME 3.20&#39;&gt;
&lt;img src=&#39;/files/2016/11/VLC_in_GNOME_Leap_42.2.jpg&#39; alt=&#39;VLC in GNOME 3.20&#39; class=&#39;img-responsive img-thumbnail&#39; itemprop=&#39;contentUrl&#39;&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em class=&#39;caption&#39; itemprop=&#39;description&#39;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;VLC in GNOME 3.20&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#39;col-sm-3&#39;&gt;&lt;div class=&#39;image no-ads-here text-center&#39; itemscope itemtype=&#39;http://schema.org/ImageObject&#39;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#39;/files/2016/11/Hexchat_xfce_42.2.jpg&#39; title=&#39;HexChat in Xfce&#39;&gt;
&lt;img src=&#39;/files/2016/11/Hexchat_xfce_42.2.jpg&#39; alt=&#39;HexChat in Xfce&#39; class=&#39;img-responsive img-thumbnail&#39; itemprop=&#39;contentUrl&#39;&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em class=&#39;caption&#39; itemprop=&#39;description&#39;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;HexChat in Xfce&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&#39;row&#39;&gt;
&lt;div class=&#39;col-sm-2&#39;&gt;
&lt;div class=&#39;image no-ads-here text-center&#39; itemscope itemtype=&#39;http://schema.org/ImageObject&#39;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#39;/assets/icons/oxygen/48x48/apps/kde.png&#39; title=&#39;&#39;&gt;
&lt;img src=&#39;/assets/icons/oxygen/48x48/apps/kde.png&#39; alt=&#39;&#39; class=&#39;img-responsive img-thumbnail&#39; itemprop=&#39;contentUrl&#39;&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&#39;col-sm-10&#39;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;kde&quot;&gt;KDE&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;openSUSE Leap 42.2 is the first to offer KDE’s Long Term Support edition of its flagship desktop software, Plasma. Feature rich with excellent performance, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.kde.org/announcements/plasma-5.8.1.php&quot;&gt;Plasma 5.8 LTS&lt;/a&gt; is the default desktop environment in openSUSE. Previous KDE users who moved away should reassess this release, with Plasma 5.8 bringing significant improvements in stability as well as new features. Plasma 5.8 improves multiple monitor support out-of-the-box in openSUSE Leap 42.2.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jump List Actions are new in KRunner and it doesn’t only open applications, but can be used to start certain actions directly when the application starts. Drag and drop support was added to bring search result to any application. &lt;a href=&quot;https://userbase.kde.org/KDE_System_Administration/Kiosk/Introduction&quot;&gt;System administrators will enjoy the Kiosk support&lt;/a&gt; from an improved Plasma in Leap 42.2. Android phone users can get phone integration with KDE Connect from the Google Play store; all they need to do is enable the KDE Connect service in the SUSE firewall module in YaST. Using KDE Connect, users can get text messages on their desktop or easily transfer files to their phone.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&#39;row&#39;&gt;
&lt;div class=&#39;col-sm-2&#39;&gt;
&lt;div class=&#39;image no-ads-here text-center&#39; itemscope itemtype=&#39;http://schema.org/ImageObject&#39;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#39;/assets/icons/hicolor/48x48/apps/pattern-gnome.png&#39; title=&#39;&#39;&gt;
&lt;img src=&#39;/assets/icons/hicolor/48x48/apps/pattern-gnome.png&#39; alt=&#39;&#39; class=&#39;img-responsive img-thumbnail&#39; itemprop=&#39;contentUrl&#39;&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&#39;col-sm-10&#39;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;gnome&quot;&gt;GNOME&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The stability of &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.gnome.org/news/2016/03/gnome-3-20-released/&quot;&gt;GNOME 3.20&lt;/a&gt; offers conservative upgrade users new privacy controls to improve per-application location access, quick access to media controls directly from the shell, and keyboard shortcuts and gestures can be easily learned with new shortcut overlay windows. Many GNOME applications have shortcut windows for 3.20, including Files, Videos, Photos, gedit, Builder, Maps and more. In each application, the shortcut window can be opened from the application menu, or by using the &lt;strong&gt;Ctrl + /&lt;/strong&gt; or &lt;strong&gt;Ctrl + F1&lt;/strong&gt; shortcut. GNOME can now access Google Drive directly from the Files application in openSUSE Leap 42.2. More than 28,000 changes were made for GNOME 3.20 by approximately 870 contributors. Check out the &lt;a href=&quot;https://help.gnome.org/misc/release-notes/3.20/&quot;&gt;release notes for GNOME 3.20&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&#39;row&#39;&gt;
&lt;div class=&#39;col-sm-2&#39;&gt;
&lt;div class=&#39;image no-ads-here text-center&#39; itemscope itemtype=&#39;http://schema.org/ImageObject&#39;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#39;/assets/icons/oxygen/48x48/places/user-desktop.png&#39; title=&#39;&#39;&gt;
&lt;img src=&#39;/assets/icons/oxygen/48x48/places/user-desktop.png&#39; alt=&#39;&#39; class=&#39;img-responsive img-thumbnail&#39; itemprop=&#39;contentUrl&#39;&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&#39;col-sm-10&#39;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;other-desktop-environments&quot;&gt;Other desktop environments&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;openSUSE Leap 42.2 offers users the option to choose their desktop; try MATE, Xfce, Enlightenment or Cinnamon. LXQt 0.11.0, which has an improved user experience thanks to several bug fixes, ships in openSUSE Leap 42.2, but is not available in the installer. LXQt 0.11.0 introduces pavucontrol-Qt, the Qt port of PulseAudio’s mixer pavucontrol the UI of which is based upon GTK.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&#39;row&#39;&gt;
&lt;div class=&#39;col-sm-2&#39;&gt;
&lt;div class=&#39;image no-ads-here text-center&#39; itemscope itemtype=&#39;http://schema.org/ImageObject&#39;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#39;/assets/icons/oxygen/48x48/categories/applications-internet.png&#39; title=&#39;&#39;&gt;
&lt;img src=&#39;/assets/icons/oxygen/48x48/categories/applications-internet.png&#39; alt=&#39;&#39; class=&#39;img-responsive img-thumbnail&#39; itemprop=&#39;contentUrl&#39;&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&#39;col-sm-10&#39;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;internationalization&quot;&gt;Internationalization&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This openSUSE release is the first to use &lt;a href=&quot;https://l10n.opensuse.org/&quot;&gt;Weblate&lt;/a&gt; to coordinate the translation of openSUSE into more than 50 languages. openSUSE’s Weblate interface enables everyone (from dedicated translators to casual contributors) to take part in the process and makes it possible to coordinate the translations of openSUSE with the ones for SUSE Enterprise Linux, boosting collaboration between community and enterprise.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;About the openSUSE Project&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The openSUSE Project is a worldwide community that promotes the use of Linux everywhere. It creates two of the world&amp;#39;s best Linux distributions, the Tumbleweed rolling-release, and Leap, the hybrid enterprise-community distribution. openSUSE is continuously working together in an open, transparent and friendly manner as part of the worldwide Free and Open Source Software community. The project is controlled by its community and relies on the contributions of individuals, working as testers, writers, translators, usability experts, artists and ambassadors or developers. The project embraces a wide variety of technology, people with different levels of expertise, speaking different languages and having different cultural backgrounds. Learn more about it on &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.opensuse.org/&quot;&gt;opensuse.org&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;This news was originally published by &lt;a href=&quot;https://news.opensuse.org/author/ddemaio/&quot;&gt;Douglas DeMaio&lt;/a&gt; at &lt;a href=&quot;https://news.opensuse.org/2016/11/16/optimal-release-for-linux-professionals-arrives-with-opensuse-leap-42-2/&quot;&gt;news.opensuse.org&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;a href=&quot;https://commons.wikimedia.org/wiki/File:Konqi_sitting_on_KDE_logo.png&quot;&gt;Konqi sitting on KDE logo&lt;/a&gt; art by &lt;a href=&quot;http://tysontan.deviantart.com/art/Konqi-ver-2-494267237&quot;&gt;Tyson Tan&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
                <pubDate>Wed, 16 Nov 2016 08:30:00 -0200</pubDate>
                <link>https://kamarada.github.io/en/2016/11/16/optimal-release-for-linux-professionals-arrives-with-opensuse-leap-42-2/</link>
                <guid isPermaLink="true">https://kamarada.github.io/en/2016/11/16/optimal-release-for-linux-professionals-arrives-with-opensuse-leap-42-2/</guid>
                
                
                    <category>en</category>
                
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>How to install openSUSE Leap Linux</title>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;It&amp;#39;s easy to install &lt;a href=&quot;/en/2015/11/04/opensuse-leap-42-1-becomes-first-hybrid-distribution/&quot;&gt;openSUSE Leap&lt;/a&gt; on your computer. Here is a brief how-to that will help you doing that. In case you need further information, refer to the &lt;a href=&quot;https://doc.opensuse.org/documentation/leap/startup/html/book.opensuse.startup/part.basics.html&quot;&gt;openSUSE Leap official documentation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&#39;image no-ads-here text-center&#39; itemscope itemtype=&#39;http://schema.org/ImageObject&#39;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#39;/files/2016/11/installation.jpg&#39; title=&#39;&#39;&gt;
&lt;img src=&#39;/files/2016/11/installation.jpg&#39; alt=&#39;&#39; class=&#39;img-responsive img-thumbnail&#39; itemprop=&#39;contentUrl&#39;&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Before installation&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Before starting, there are a few things you should be aware of.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;openSUSE supports most &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/IBM_Personal_Computer&quot;&gt;PC&lt;/a&gt; hardware components and can be installed alongside your current operating system (maybe your computer already has &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.microsoft.com/windows/&quot;&gt;Windows&lt;/a&gt; installed, for example). You don&amp;#39;t need to remove it in order to install openSUSE.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, to ensure smooth operation of openSUSE Leap, your computer should satisfy the following &lt;a href=&quot;https://doc.opensuse.org/documentation/leap/startup/html/book.opensuse.startup/art.opensuse.installquick.html#sec.osuse.installquick.sysreqs&quot;&gt;requirements&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.intel.com/&quot;&gt;Intel&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.amd.com/&quot;&gt;AMD&lt;/a&gt; or compatible 64-bit processor (&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.reddit.com/r/openSUSE/comments/3d711c/will_leap_42_support_32bit_machines_given_that/&quot;&gt;32-bit processors are not supported&lt;/a&gt;, but if your computer is at least relatively new, there is a good chance its processor is 64-bit);&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;1GB physical RAM (2GB or more recommended); and&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;5GB available disk space (more recommended for personal files and software to be installed in the future).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you are going to install openSUSE Leap on a laptop, make sure its battery is fully charged and its AC adapter is plugged in. Do not remove the battery or unplug the AC adapter during installation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Getting started&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Which media are you using to install openSUSE Leap? If it&amp;#39;s the &lt;a href=&quot;/en/2015/12/09/what-is-a-livecd-dvd-usb/&quot;&gt;LiveDVD built by the Linux Kamarada Project&lt;/a&gt;, put it into your computer&amp;#39;s DVD-drive. If it&amp;#39;s a &lt;a href=&quot;/en/2015/12/09/what-is-a-livecd-dvd-usb/&quot;&gt;LiveUSB&lt;/a&gt;, insert it on one of your computer&amp;#39;s USB ports. Then, in both cases, restart your computer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Within moments, you will get to the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.kde.org/&quot;&gt;KDE&amp;#39;s Plasma desktop&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&#39;image no-ads-here text-center&#39; itemscope itemtype=&#39;http://schema.org/ImageObject&#39;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#39;/files/2016/11/installation-01-en.jpg&#39; title=&#39;&#39;&gt;
&lt;img src=&#39;/files/2016/11/installation-01-en.jpg&#39; alt=&#39;&#39; class=&#39;img-responsive img-thumbnail&#39; itemprop=&#39;contentUrl&#39;&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Click the &lt;strong&gt;Install&lt;/strong&gt; icon on the desktop to start installer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;1) Language, keyboard layout and license&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On the first screen, you are presented to the language and keyboard layout settings and the &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.opensuse.org/openSUSE:License&quot;&gt;openSUSE Leap license&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&#39;image no-ads-here text-center&#39; itemscope itemtype=&#39;http://schema.org/ImageObject&#39;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#39;/files/2016/11/installation-02-en.jpg&#39; title=&#39;&#39;&gt;
&lt;img src=&#39;/files/2016/11/installation-02-en.jpg&#39; alt=&#39;&#39; class=&#39;img-responsive img-thumbnail&#39; itemprop=&#39;contentUrl&#39;&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Check that the language and keyboard layout settings are as desired. The installer offers a text field in which you can type something to test your keyboard. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You don&amp;#39;t need to worry about the software license: since openSUSE is a &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.gnu.org/philosophy/free-sw.html&quot;&gt;software &lt;em&gt;libre&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, its license does not limit your use. You can read it just to know your rights as an openSUSE user.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When you finish, click &lt;strong&gt;Next&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;2) Clock and time zone&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;div class=&#39;image no-ads-here text-center&#39; itemscope itemtype=&#39;http://schema.org/ImageObject&#39;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#39;/files/2016/11/installation-03-en.jpg&#39; title=&#39;&#39;&gt;
&lt;img src=&#39;/files/2016/11/installation-03-en.jpg&#39; alt=&#39;&#39; class=&#39;img-responsive img-thumbnail&#39; itemprop=&#39;contentUrl&#39;&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Check that your time zone, date and time settings are correct.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you need to change the time zone, click on the map closest to your current location or use the &lt;strong&gt;Region&lt;/strong&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;Time Zone&lt;/strong&gt; dropdown menus below the map.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If your computer will have only Linux installed, it&amp;#39;s recommended to keep the &lt;strong&gt;Hardware Clock Set to UTC&lt;/strong&gt; option checked. If you are installing Linux alongside Windows or other operating system, make sure you unckeck that box.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you need further information about that screen, please refer to the &lt;a href=&quot;https://doc.opensuse.org/documentation/leap/startup/html/book.opensuse.startup/cha.inst.html#sec.i.yast2.timezone&quot;&gt;openSUSE Leap official documentation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When you finish, click &lt;strong&gt;Next&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;3) Partitioning&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;div class=&#39;image no-ads-here text-center&#39; itemscope itemtype=&#39;http://schema.org/ImageObject&#39;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#39;/files/2016/11/installation-04-en.jpg&#39; title=&#39;&#39;&gt;
&lt;img src=&#39;/files/2016/11/installation-04-en.jpg&#39; alt=&#39;&#39; class=&#39;img-responsive img-thumbnail&#39; itemprop=&#39;contentUrl&#39;&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By default, openSUSE proposes to create three new partitions:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;/&lt;/code&gt; (root), for system files;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;/home&lt;/code&gt;, for personal files of users; and&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.linux.com/news/all-about-linux-swap-space&quot;&gt;swap&lt;/a&gt;, which is used as a supplement for RAM, similar to the &lt;a href=&quot;https://support.microsoft.com/kb/2160852&quot;&gt;page file&lt;/a&gt; in Windows.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If your computer is in &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.opensuse.org/openSUSE:UEFI&quot;&gt;UEFI&lt;/a&gt; mode (as is the case in the figure), possibly the installer will suggest creating a fourth partition, which is the &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/EFI_system_partition&quot;&gt;ESP&lt;/a&gt;. If your computer came with Windows pre-installed, probably it already has an ESP, so its creation is not suggested.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;#39;m not going to dive into details about partitioning here, as that would be a subject for an entire (and long) post. If you need more information, I suggest you take a look at the &lt;a href=&quot;https://doc.opensuse.org/documentation/leap/startup/html/book.opensuse.startup/cha.inst.html#sec.i.yast2.inst_mode.partitioning&quot;&gt;openSUSE Leap official documentation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Usually the openSUSE installer is smart enough to suggest you the best possible partitioning setting for your computer. Change it only if you know what you are doing, since improper partitioning can lead to accidental loss of data.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When you finish, click &lt;strong&gt;Next&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;4) Username and password&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;div class=&#39;image no-ads-here text-center&#39; itemscope itemtype=&#39;http://schema.org/ImageObject&#39;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#39;/files/2016/11/installation-05-en.jpg&#39; title=&#39;&#39;&gt;
&lt;img src=&#39;/files/2016/11/installation-05-en.jpg&#39; alt=&#39;&#39; class=&#39;img-responsive img-thumbnail&#39; itemprop=&#39;contentUrl&#39;&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On that screen, you are going to create an user account for you. Enter your full name and the desired username and password.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If security is a concern, please note that the installer suggests to:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;use the same password for the administrator user (in Linux, it is called superuser or &lt;em&gt;root&lt;/em&gt;); and&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;automatically log in your user account when the computer turns on.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Those options are suggested for convenience, but actually they make your system a little less secure. Consider unchecking the &lt;strong&gt;Use this password for system administrator&lt;/strong&gt; option and setting up a different password for the root user. Also, unchecking the &lt;strong&gt;Automatic Login&lt;/strong&gt; option will enforce that an username and password must be provided to use the computer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When you finish, click &lt;strong&gt;Next&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The installer may complain about your password if it is considered easy to guess:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&#39;image no-ads-here text-center&#39; itemscope itemtype=&#39;http://schema.org/ImageObject&#39;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#39;/files/2016/11/installation-06-en.jpg&#39; title=&#39;&#39;&gt;
&lt;img src=&#39;/files/2016/11/installation-06-en.jpg&#39; alt=&#39;&#39; class=&#39;img-responsive img-thumbnail&#39; itemprop=&#39;contentUrl&#39;&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If that is the case, it is strongly recommended that you click &lt;strong&gt;No&lt;/strong&gt; and set up a safer password.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you need help on how to elaborate a strong password, you may check this Lifehacker&amp;#39;s post &lt;a href=&quot;http://lifehacker.com/four-methods-to-create-a-secure-password-youll-actually-1601854240&quot;&gt;Four Methods to Create a Secure Password You&amp;#39;ll Actually Remember&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;5) Installation overview&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;div class=&#39;image no-ads-here text-center&#39; itemscope itemtype=&#39;http://schema.org/ImageObject&#39;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#39;/files/2016/11/installation-07-en.jpg&#39; title=&#39;&#39;&gt;
&lt;img src=&#39;/files/2016/11/installation-07-en.jpg&#39; alt=&#39;&#39; class=&#39;img-responsive img-thumbnail&#39; itemprop=&#39;contentUrl&#39;&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Check that everything is as desired. Once you click &lt;strong&gt;Install&lt;/strong&gt;, there will be no way back.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you need to change any setting, click on its link to go to the corresponding screen.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Else, if you are ready, click &lt;strong&gt;Install&lt;/strong&gt;. A confirmation message is shown:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&#39;image no-ads-here text-center&#39; itemscope itemtype=&#39;http://schema.org/ImageObject&#39;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#39;/files/2016/11/installation-08-en.jpg&#39; title=&#39;&#39;&gt;
&lt;img src=&#39;/files/2016/11/installation-08-en.jpg&#39; alt=&#39;&#39; class=&#39;img-responsive img-thumbnail&#39; itemprop=&#39;contentUrl&#39;&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Click &lt;strong&gt;Install&lt;/strong&gt; to start &lt;em&gt;de facto&lt;/em&gt; installing openSUSE Leap.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;6) Actual installation&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;div class=&#39;image no-ads-here text-center&#39; itemscope itemtype=&#39;http://schema.org/ImageObject&#39;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#39;/files/2016/11/installation-09-en.jpg&#39; title=&#39;&#39;&gt;
&lt;img src=&#39;/files/2016/11/installation-09-en.jpg&#39; alt=&#39;&#39; class=&#39;img-responsive img-thumbnail&#39; itemprop=&#39;contentUrl&#39;&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now the actual installation is performed. That screen shows its progress in detail.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Even though you are allowed to use your computer during installation, avoid doing that, so it won&amp;#39;t crash and the system being installed won&amp;#39;t be corrupted, what could turn your computer unusable.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When the installation is done, the installer asks you to reboot your computer:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&#39;image no-ads-here text-center&#39; itemscope itemtype=&#39;http://schema.org/ImageObject&#39;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#39;/files/2016/11/installation-10-en.jpg&#39; title=&#39;&#39;&gt;
&lt;img src=&#39;/files/2016/11/installation-10-en.jpg&#39; alt=&#39;&#39; class=&#39;img-responsive img-thumbnail&#39; itemprop=&#39;contentUrl&#39;&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That&amp;#39;s all folks!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now you just need to restart your computer and start using openSUSE Leap.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Have a lot of fun!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
                <pubDate>Tue, 15 Nov 2016 23:59:59 -0200</pubDate>
                <link>https://kamarada.github.io/en/2016/11/15/how-to-install-opensuse-leap-linux/</link>
                <guid isPermaLink="true">https://kamarada.github.io/en/2016/11/15/how-to-install-opensuse-leap-linux/</guid>
                
                
                    <category>en</category>
                
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>How to upgrade from openSUSE Leap 42.1 to 42.2</title>
                <description>&lt;div class=&#39;image no-ads-here text-center&#39; itemscope itemtype=&#39;http://schema.org/ImageObject&#39;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#39;/files/2016/10/upgrade.png&#39; title=&#39;Source: [openSUSE News](https://news.opensuse.org/2016/09/22/new-leap-beta-adds-plasma-5-8-beta/)&#39;&gt;
&lt;img src=&#39;/files/2016/10/upgrade.png&#39; alt=&#39;Source: [openSUSE News](https://news.opensuse.org/2016/09/22/new-leap-beta-adds-plasma-5-8-beta/)&#39; class=&#39;img-responsive img-thumbnail&#39; itemprop=&#39;contentUrl&#39;&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;

&lt;em class=&#39;caption&#39; itemprop=&#39;description&#39;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&quot;https://news.opensuse.org/2016/09/22/new-leap-beta-adds-plasma-5-8-beta/&quot;&gt;openSUSE News&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;/em&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Being able to upgrade from one release to another is a certainty &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.opensuse.org&quot;&gt;openSUSE&lt;/a&gt; users have. For 3 years now I use openSUSE Linux and I always upgraded without an issue. I started to use openSUSE when it was 12.2, shortly before the &lt;a href=&quot;https://news.opensuse.org/2013/03/13/opensuse-12-3-free-open-and-awesome/&quot;&gt;12.3 release in May 2013&lt;/a&gt;. Since then I went through 5 upgrades: from 12.2 to 12.3, to 13.1, to 13.2, to Leap 42.1 (in fact, there was a leap, as we have seen on &lt;a href=&quot;/en/2015/11/04/opensuse-leap-42-1-becomes-first-hybrid-distribution/&quot;&gt;that release&amp;#39;s announcement&lt;/a&gt;) and this week to 42.2, even before it was officially launched.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The next openSUSE Leap release, 42.2, already passed alfa and beta phases and had its first release candidate (RC) launched on &lt;a href=&quot;https://news.opensuse.org/2016/10/18/release-candidate-available-for-opensuse-leap-42-2/&quot;&gt;October 18&lt;/a&gt;. That means most of the tests have ended. That release is very close to the final one, scheduled to &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.opensuse.org/openSUSE:Roadmap&quot;&gt;November 16&lt;/a&gt;. Until then, openSUSE Leap should receive no more than a few finishing touches.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Checkout this post to know beforehand how to upgrade your openSUSE Leap installation from 42.1 to 42.2. If you are the kind of person who prefers safety to adventure, here you are going to see what you will do on November 16, after the official release of openSUSE Leap 42.2. If you prefer adventure, like me, you are going to see what you can do to get the coming 42.2 right now. At least both the computers I use at home and work are now working well with openSUSE Leap 42.2 RC 1.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To better organize the text, I split the upgrade process in 6 steps.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;A few notes&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The how-to I present here is based on the openSUSE wiki&amp;#39;s &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.opensuse.org/SDB:System_upgrade&quot;&gt;SDB:System upgrade&lt;/a&gt; page, whose instructions I followed to upgrade my system. That page has changed little since I started using openSUSE. It presents a safe upgrade procedure, which should work for most cases, but requires some things be observed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;You must be using the immediately previous openSUSE release.&lt;/strong&gt; It means that if you want to upgrade to 42.2, now you must be using 42.1. Hopping over one or more releases is not supported and probably will not work. So if you use openSUSE 13.2, for example, you must first upgrade to Leap 42.1, and then to Leap 42.2 (note that the leap here is just in numbers, &lt;a href=&quot;/en/2015/11/04/opensuse-leap-42-1-becomes-first-hybrid-distribution/&quot;&gt;the Leap 42.1 release is indeed the successor of 13.2&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Your openSUSE installation must be up to date&lt;/strong&gt; with the latest updates for the release you are currently running. To learn how to update your system, read the &lt;a href=&quot;/en/2016/10/22/keep-your-system-always-up-to-date/&quot;&gt;previous post&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;You should read about the openSUSE release you are going to install.&lt;/strong&gt; Read the &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.opensuse.org/openSUSE:Most_annoying_bugs&quot;&gt;list of annoying bugs&lt;/a&gt; to be prepared for upcoming problems, how to prevent and/or solve them. Also, read the &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.opensuse.org/openSUSE:Release_Notes&quot;&gt;release notes&lt;/a&gt;, which list changes and glitches in the new release.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;You must backup all important data.&lt;/strong&gt; Even though upgrading openSUSE is a safe procedure, that resembles upgrading &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.debian.org/&quot;&gt;Debian&lt;/a&gt;, it is not perfect. Winning the lottery is difficult, but eventually someone wins. Something may go wrong during upgrade, but it is difficult, even more if you do things cautiously. Anyway, it never hurts to make a backup of your personal files as a precaution, especially if the &lt;code&gt;/home&lt;/code&gt; directory is not on a dedicated partition. If the computer is one that should not be down for long (a server, for example), consider backing up the entire system, so you will be able to restore it immediately if something does not work as expected.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;You should not use third party repositories during upgrade.&lt;/strong&gt; Before upgrading, we are going to remove all third party repositories. Doing that may cause third party software to be removed during upgrade. If that happens, you may try to reinstall it later. It does not mean that you cannot upgrade with third party repositories enabled, but using only the official repositories is more guaranteed. That way, the base system will be upgraded to a new stable, solid and reliable base. Then, on top of that base, you can install whatever you want. Do different only if you know what you are doing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I also recommend that you read this entire page before you actually upgrade. Once you know the whole process, you will be able to better schedule it. You can even use your computer while downloading packages, but after you start upgrading, your computer will become usable again only after upgrading is completed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Before we begin, I would like to make one more note, for those who want to upgrade to openSUSE Leap 42.2 before the final release date. If that is your case, please note that you will need to repeat the steps &amp;quot;download packages&amp;quot; and &amp;quot;upgrade your system&amp;quot;, the last two steps in this tutorial (5 and 6), for each new release of this version. So, you will repeat those steps on November 2, when Leap 42.2 RC 2 is scheduled to be released, and on November 16, after the final release of Leap 42.2.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;1) Update your current system&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Before beginning, make sure your openSUSE installation is up to date.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As we have seen in the &lt;a href=&quot;/en/2016/10/22/keep-your-system-always-up-to-date/&quot;&gt;previous post&lt;/a&gt;, if your system is up to date, the &lt;strong&gt;Software Updates&lt;/strong&gt; icon informs that to you:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&#39;image no-ads-here text-center&#39; itemscope itemtype=&#39;http://schema.org/ImageObject&#39;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#39;/files/2016/10/sw-updates-05-en.jpg&#39; title=&#39;&#39;&gt;
&lt;img src=&#39;/files/2016/10/sw-updates-05-en.jpg&#39; alt=&#39;&#39; class=&#39;img-responsive img-thumbnail&#39; itemprop=&#39;contentUrl&#39;&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Or, if you prefer using the command line interface (CLI), you can check if your system is up to date running &lt;code&gt;zypper up&lt;/code&gt; as root. If that is the case, it returns &amp;quot;Nothing to do&amp;quot;:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&#39;image no-ads-here text-center&#39; itemscope itemtype=&#39;http://schema.org/ImageObject&#39;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#39;/files/2016/10/sw-updates-cmd-05-en.jpg&#39; title=&#39;&#39;&gt;
&lt;img src=&#39;/files/2016/10/sw-updates-cmd-05-en.jpg&#39; alt=&#39;&#39; class=&#39;img-responsive img-thumbnail&#39; itemprop=&#39;contentUrl&#39;&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Take a look at &lt;a href=&quot;/en/2016/10/22/keep-your-system-always-up-to-date/&quot;&gt;that post&lt;/a&gt; to see how to update your openSUSE.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let me clarify something, in case it sounds confusing: by &lt;strong&gt;update&lt;/strong&gt; we mean update just a few packages without actually moving from one release to another (e.g. from 42.1 to 42.2). By &lt;strong&gt;upgrade&lt;/strong&gt; we mean update the whole system to move to the next release.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I use the graphical user interface (GUI) whenever possible, but using the CLI brings us some advantages: &lt;strong&gt;zypper&lt;/strong&gt; allows us to only download updates in a first moment and then install them later. If you are not familiar with the CLI, you will realize that it is not difficult to use.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Note that, almost always, you can use the CLI without actually leaving the desktop environment through the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.kde.org/applications/system/konsole/&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Konsole&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; application. To start it, open the &lt;strong&gt;Application Menu&lt;/strong&gt;, point to &lt;strong&gt;System&lt;/strong&gt;, and then click &lt;strong&gt;Konsole&lt;/strong&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&#39;image no-ads-here text-center&#39; itemscope itemtype=&#39;http://schema.org/ImageObject&#39;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#39;/files/2016/10/upgrade-01-en.jpg&#39; title=&#39;&#39;&gt;
&lt;img src=&#39;/files/2016/10/upgrade-01-en.jpg&#39; alt=&#39;&#39; class=&#39;img-responsive img-thumbnail&#39; itemprop=&#39;contentUrl&#39;&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you are familiar with &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.microsoft.com/windows/&quot;&gt;Windows&lt;/a&gt;, perhaps you think Konsole resembles Windows&amp;#39; &lt;strong&gt;Command Prompt&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;2) Backup your current repositories&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Actually, this step is optional.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You may want to back up your current list of repositories to return them after upgrading. openSUSE saves repository settings in the &lt;code&gt;/etc/zypp/repos.d&lt;/code&gt; folder. It has some text files, one for each repository. Let&amp;#39;s backup that folder using the CLI.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Get root privileges running &lt;code&gt;su&lt;/code&gt; (if you are not familiar with the CLI, by &amp;quot;running &lt;code&gt;su&lt;/code&gt;&amp;quot;, we mean &amp;quot;type &lt;code&gt;su&lt;/code&gt; and hit &lt;strong&gt;Enter&lt;/strong&gt;&amp;quot;). You will be asked the root password, which you must provide to continue (type the root password and hit &lt;strong&gt;Enter&lt;/strong&gt;, note that the password is not displayed, not even masked as ******, this is normal).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then, order the copy running &lt;code&gt;cp -Rv /etc/zypp/repos.d /etc/zypp/repos.d.old&lt;/code&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&#39;image no-ads-here text-center&#39; itemscope itemtype=&#39;http://schema.org/ImageObject&#39;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#39;/files/2016/10/upgrade-02-en.jpg&#39; title=&#39;&#39;&gt;
&lt;img src=&#39;/files/2016/10/upgrade-02-en.jpg&#39; alt=&#39;&#39; class=&#39;img-responsive img-thumbnail&#39; itemprop=&#39;contentUrl&#39;&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That command copies the &lt;code&gt;repos.d&lt;/code&gt; folder, in &lt;code&gt;/etc/zypp&lt;/code&gt;, to another folder in the same place, called &lt;code&gt;repos.d.old&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have not made a backup of your data yet, consider doing that now.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;3) Clean up repositories&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As already mentioned, for upgrade we use only the &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.opensuse.org/Package_repositories#Official_Repositories&quot;&gt;official repositories&lt;/a&gt;. To be more precise, just two of them:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;openSUSE-Leap-42.2-OSS&lt;/strong&gt;: the main repository, contains &lt;a href=&quot;https://opensource.org/osd-annotated&quot;&gt;open source software&lt;/a&gt; only.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;URL: &lt;a href=&quot;http://download.opensuse.org/distribution/leap/42.2/repo/oss/&quot;&gt;http://download.opensuse.org/distribution/leap/42.2/repo/oss/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;openSUSE-Leap-42.2-Update&lt;/strong&gt;: contains official updates for OSS packages.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;URL: &lt;a href=&quot;http://download.opensuse.org/update/leap/42.2/oss/&quot;&gt;http://download.opensuse.org/update/leap/42.2/oss/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let&amp;#39;s clean up our repositories removing any repository we won&amp;#39;t need (including any &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.opensuse.org/Additional_package_repositories&quot;&gt;third party repositories&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Start the YaST Control Center by opening the &lt;strong&gt;Application Menu&lt;/strong&gt;, pointing to &lt;strong&gt;System&lt;/strong&gt;, and then clicking on &lt;strong&gt;YaST&lt;/strong&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&#39;image no-ads-here text-center&#39; itemscope itemtype=&#39;http://schema.org/ImageObject&#39;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#39;/files/2016/10/linux-ntp-01.jpg&#39; title=&#39;&#39;&gt;
&lt;img src=&#39;/files/2016/10/linux-ntp-01.jpg&#39; alt=&#39;&#39; class=&#39;img-responsive img-thumbnail&#39; itemprop=&#39;contentUrl&#39;&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You will be asked the root password.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Select the &lt;strong&gt;Software&lt;/strong&gt; category, then click on &lt;strong&gt;Software Repositories&lt;/strong&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&#39;image no-ads-here text-center&#39; itemscope itemtype=&#39;http://schema.org/ImageObject&#39;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#39;/files/2016/10/upgrade-03-en.png&#39; title=&#39;&#39;&gt;
&lt;img src=&#39;/files/2016/10/upgrade-03-en.png&#39; alt=&#39;&#39; class=&#39;img-responsive img-thumbnail&#39; itemprop=&#39;contentUrl&#39;&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You are presented to your system&amp;#39;s repository list:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&#39;image no-ads-here text-center&#39; itemscope itemtype=&#39;http://schema.org/ImageObject&#39;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#39;/files/2016/10/upgrade-04-en.jpg&#39; title=&#39;&#39;&gt;
&lt;img src=&#39;/files/2016/10/upgrade-04-en.jpg&#39; alt=&#39;&#39; class=&#39;img-responsive img-thumbnail&#39; itemprop=&#39;contentUrl&#39;&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For each repository that is neither &lt;strong&gt;openSUSE-Leap-42.1-OSS&lt;/strong&gt; nor &lt;strong&gt;openSUSE-Leap-42.1-Update&lt;/strong&gt;, select it in the list and click on &lt;strong&gt;Delete&lt;/strong&gt; (no typo, we are managing old repositories, the 42.1 ones, we are going to switch to the new ones soon).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;YaST will ask you for confirmation. Click on &lt;strong&gt;Yes&lt;/strong&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&#39;image no-ads-here text-center&#39; itemscope itemtype=&#39;http://schema.org/ImageObject&#39;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#39;/files/2016/10/upgrade-05-en.jpg&#39; title=&#39;&#39;&gt;
&lt;img src=&#39;/files/2016/10/upgrade-05-en.jpg&#39; alt=&#39;&#39; class=&#39;img-responsive img-thumbnail&#39; itemprop=&#39;contentUrl&#39;&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Do that with all repositories, until the list has only &lt;strong&gt;openSUSE-Leap-42.1-OSS&lt;/strong&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;openSUSE-Leap-42.1-Update&lt;/strong&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&#39;image no-ads-here text-center&#39; itemscope itemtype=&#39;http://schema.org/ImageObject&#39;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#39;/files/2016/10/upgrade-06-en.jpg&#39; title=&#39;&#39;&gt;
&lt;img src=&#39;/files/2016/10/upgrade-06-en.jpg&#39; alt=&#39;&#39; class=&#39;img-responsive img-thumbnail&#39; itemprop=&#39;contentUrl&#39;&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Maybe those repositories are named differently on your system. If that is the case, try to recognize them by their &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Uniform_Resource_Locator&quot;&gt;URL&lt;/a&gt; instead of their name. If you don&amp;#39;t find them, there is no problem: delete all repositories and add just the new ones.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;4) Switch to the new repositories&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now let&amp;#39;s move to the new release&amp;#39;s repositories.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Select the &lt;strong&gt;openSUSE-42.1-Leap-OSS&lt;/strong&gt; repository and click on &lt;strong&gt;Edit&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Replace &lt;code&gt;42.1&lt;/code&gt; by &lt;code&gt;42.2&lt;/code&gt; where necessary and click on &lt;strong&gt;OK&lt;/strong&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&#39;image no-ads-here text-center&#39; itemscope itemtype=&#39;http://schema.org/ImageObject&#39;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#39;/files/2016/10/upgrade-07-en.jpg&#39; title=&#39;&#39;&gt;
&lt;img src=&#39;/files/2016/10/upgrade-07-en.jpg&#39; alt=&#39;&#39; class=&#39;img-responsive img-thumbnail&#39; itemprop=&#39;contentUrl&#39;&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You are presented to the &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.opensuse.org/openSUSE:License&quot;&gt;openSUSE Leap 42.2 license&lt;/a&gt;. You can read it to know your rights as an openSUSE user. When you are finished, click on &lt;strong&gt;Next&lt;/strong&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&#39;image no-ads-here text-center&#39; itemscope itemtype=&#39;http://schema.org/ImageObject&#39;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#39;/files/2016/10/upgrade-08-en.jpg&#39; title=&#39;&#39;&gt;
&lt;img src=&#39;/files/2016/10/upgrade-08-en.jpg&#39; alt=&#39;&#39; class=&#39;img-responsive img-thumbnail&#39; itemprop=&#39;contentUrl&#39;&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Do the same for the &lt;strong&gt;openSUSE-Leap-42.1-Update&lt;/strong&gt; repository.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At the end, your system&amp;#39;s repository list should look like this:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&#39;image no-ads-here text-center&#39; itemscope itemtype=&#39;http://schema.org/ImageObject&#39;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#39;/files/2016/10/upgrade-09-en.jpg&#39; title=&#39;&#39;&gt;
&lt;img src=&#39;/files/2016/10/upgrade-09-en.jpg&#39; alt=&#39;&#39; class=&#39;img-responsive img-thumbnail&#39; itemprop=&#39;contentUrl&#39;&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Click on &lt;strong&gt;OK&lt;/strong&gt; to save changes. You can close YaST.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;5) Download packages&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We can start downloading the packages of the new openSUSE release.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Back to CLI, run &lt;code&gt;zypper ref&lt;/code&gt; to retrieve the list of available packages from the new repositories. Then, run &lt;code&gt;zypper dup --download-only&lt;/code&gt; (&lt;code&gt;dup&lt;/code&gt; is an acronym for &lt;em&gt;distribution upgrade&lt;/em&gt;):&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&#39;image no-ads-here text-center&#39; itemscope itemtype=&#39;http://schema.org/ImageObject&#39;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#39;/files/2016/10/upgrade-10-en.jpg&#39; title=&#39;&#39;&gt;
&lt;img src=&#39;/files/2016/10/upgrade-10-en.jpg&#39; alt=&#39;&#39; class=&#39;img-responsive img-thumbnail&#39; itemprop=&#39;contentUrl&#39;&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;zypper&lt;/strong&gt; spends some time &amp;quot;thinking&amp;quot;. Soon after, it shows what it needs to do in order to upgrade openSUSE to the next release and asks if you want to continue:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&#39;image no-ads-here text-center&#39; itemscope itemtype=&#39;http://schema.org/ImageObject&#39;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#39;/files/2016/10/upgrade-11-en.jpg&#39; title=&#39;&#39;&gt;
&lt;img src=&#39;/files/2016/10/upgrade-11-en.jpg&#39; alt=&#39;&#39; class=&#39;img-responsive img-thumbnail&#39; itemprop=&#39;contentUrl&#39;&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That list of actions is similar to that produced by &lt;code&gt;zypper up&lt;/code&gt;, presented in the &lt;a href=&quot;/en/2016/10/22/keep-your-system-always-up-to-date/&quot;&gt;previous post&lt;/a&gt;. However, as we are now doing a distribution upgrade, and not an ordinary update, the list of what needs to be done is much bigger.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Review that list carefully. You can go up or down using the scrollbar at the right of the window or the mouse wheel (scroll wheel) if you are using Konsole, or the &lt;strong&gt;Shift + Page Up&lt;/strong&gt; / &lt;strong&gt;Shift + Page Down&lt;/strong&gt; key combinations if you are using a purely textual interface (they also work in Konsole).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The default option is to continue (&lt;strong&gt;s&lt;/strong&gt;). If you agree, you can just hit &lt;strong&gt;Enter&lt;/strong&gt; and downloading of the new packages will start. Meanwhile, you can use your computer normally. The upgrade itself has not started yet.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Note that &lt;strong&gt;zypper&lt;/strong&gt; only downloads packages, it does not start upgrading:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&#39;image no-ads-here text-center&#39; itemscope itemtype=&#39;http://schema.org/ImageObject&#39;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#39;/files/2016/10/upgrade-12-en.jpg&#39; title=&#39;&#39;&gt;
&lt;img src=&#39;/files/2016/10/upgrade-12-en.jpg&#39; alt=&#39;&#39; class=&#39;img-responsive img-thumbnail&#39; itemprop=&#39;contentUrl&#39;&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That&amp;#39;s because we invoked it with the &lt;code&gt;--download-only&lt;/code&gt; option.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Finish what you are doing and save any open files so we can start upgrading. Note that upgrading may take several minutes and you will be able to continue using your computer only after it is complete.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;6) Upgrade your system&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now that we have already downloaded all the packages needed to update our openSUSE Leap 42.1 to 42.2, we need to leave the desktop environment and use the pure textual interface to perform the upgrade. Here on, you cannot use Konsole.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That is necessary because the desktop itself will be upgraded. If we run the upgrade while still using the desktop, it may stop/crash, causing the upgrade to abort, which in turn left the system in an inconsistent, unpredictable state.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Consider open this page on another computer (or on a mobile device), print it or take note of the next actions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you are upgrading a laptop system, make sure its battery is fully charged and its AC adapter is plugged in. Do not remove the battery or unplug the AC adapter during the upgrade. We want to prevent any possibility of problem.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Logout by by opening the &lt;strong&gt;Application Menu&lt;/strong&gt;, pointing to &lt;strong&gt;Power / Session&lt;/strong&gt; and clicking on &lt;strong&gt;Logout&lt;/strong&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&#39;image no-ads-here text-center&#39; itemscope itemtype=&#39;http://schema.org/ImageObject&#39;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#39;/files/2016/10/logout-kde-en.jpg&#39; title=&#39;&#39;&gt;
&lt;img src=&#39;/files/2016/10/logout-kde-en.jpg&#39; alt=&#39;&#39; class=&#39;img-responsive img-thumbnail&#39; itemprop=&#39;contentUrl&#39;&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You are presented to the login screen where you could enter your username and password to start a new desktop session:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&#39;image no-ads-here text-center&#39; itemscope itemtype=&#39;http://schema.org/ImageObject&#39;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#39;/files/2016/10/upgrade-13-en.jpg&#39; title=&#39;&#39;&gt;
&lt;img src=&#39;/files/2016/10/upgrade-13-en.jpg&#39; alt=&#39;&#39; class=&#39;img-responsive img-thumbnail&#39; itemprop=&#39;contentUrl&#39;&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But that&amp;#39;s not what we want. Press the &lt;strong&gt;Ctrl + Alt + F1&lt;/strong&gt; key combination to switch to a purely textual interface:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&#39;image no-ads-here text-center&#39; itemscope itemtype=&#39;http://schema.org/ImageObject&#39;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#39;/files/2016/10/upgrade-14.jpg&#39; title=&#39;&#39;&gt;
&lt;img src=&#39;/files/2016/10/upgrade-14.jpg&#39; alt=&#39;&#39; class=&#39;img-responsive img-thumbnail&#39; itemprop=&#39;contentUrl&#39;&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If that was new to you, know that Linux provides six &lt;a href=&quot;http://opensuse-guide.org/command.php&quot;&gt;consoles&lt;/a&gt; besides the graphical interface. You can use the keys F1 to F6 in that same combination (&lt;strong&gt;Ctrl + Alt + F1&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;Ctrl + Alt + F2&lt;/strong&gt; and so on) to switch between consoles, pressing &lt;strong&gt;Ctrl + Alt + F7&lt;/strong&gt; you can return to the graphical interface.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But let&amp;#39;s stand on the first console.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Login as root (to do that, type &lt;code&gt;root&lt;/code&gt; and press &lt;strong&gt;Enter&lt;/strong&gt;, then enter the root password and press &lt;strong&gt;Enter&lt;/strong&gt; again).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let&amp;#39;s switch from &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Runlevel&quot;&gt;runlevel&lt;/a&gt; 5, the default runlevel, in which the system provides the GUI, to the runlevel 3, in which we have only the CLI and network connection.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.opensuse.org/SDB:Switch_runlevel&quot;&gt;change to runlevel&lt;/a&gt; 3, run &lt;code&gt;init 3&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Finally, we are going to start the distribution upgrade itself. Run &lt;code&gt;zypper --no-refresh dup&lt;/code&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&#39;image no-ads-here text-center&#39; itemscope itemtype=&#39;http://schema.org/ImageObject&#39;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#39;/files/2016/10/upgrade-15.jpg&#39; title=&#39;&#39;&gt;
&lt;img src=&#39;/files/2016/10/upgrade-15.jpg&#39; alt=&#39;&#39; class=&#39;img-responsive img-thumbnail&#39; itemprop=&#39;contentUrl&#39;&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The &lt;code&gt;--no-refresh&lt;/code&gt; option makes &lt;strong&gt;zypper&lt;/strong&gt; not retrieve the list of packages from repositories. Using that option, we ensure that &lt;strong&gt;zypper&lt;/strong&gt; won&amp;#39;t try to download any package in addition to those we have already downloaded. That can be useful especially for laptops, which may lose the Wi-Fi connection when leaving the GUI.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As before, &lt;strong&gt;zipper&lt;/strong&gt; will compute the upgrade and show what it will do:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&#39;image no-ads-here text-center&#39; itemscope itemtype=&#39;http://schema.org/ImageObject&#39;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#39;/files/2016/10/upgrade-16.jpg&#39; title=&#39;&#39;&gt;
&lt;img src=&#39;/files/2016/10/upgrade-16.jpg&#39; alt=&#39;&#39; class=&#39;img-responsive img-thumbnail&#39; itemprop=&#39;contentUrl&#39;&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Note that all the needed packages have already been downloaded: at the end, &lt;strong&gt;zypper&lt;/strong&gt;&amp;#39;s report shows &amp;quot;Overall download size: 0 B. Already cached: 1.62 GiB&amp;quot;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Just press &lt;strong&gt;Enter&lt;/strong&gt; to start upgrading.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;zypper&lt;/strong&gt; skips downloading packages and goes straight to upgrading:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&#39;image no-ads-here text-center&#39; itemscope itemtype=&#39;http://schema.org/ImageObject&#39;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#39;/files/2016/10/upgrade-17.jpg&#39; title=&#39;&#39;&gt;
&lt;img src=&#39;/files/2016/10/upgrade-17.jpg&#39; alt=&#39;&#39; class=&#39;img-responsive img-thumbnail&#39; itemprop=&#39;contentUrl&#39;&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Distribution upgrade may take several minutes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When it finishes, as happened in the &lt;a href=&quot;/en/2016/10/22/keep-your-system-always-up-to-date/&quot;&gt;previous post&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;zypper&lt;/strong&gt; suggests to restart. Let&amp;#39;s do that by running &lt;code&gt;reboot&lt;/code&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&#39;image no-ads-here text-center&#39; itemscope itemtype=&#39;http://schema.org/ImageObject&#39;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#39;/files/2016/10/upgrade-18.jpg&#39; title=&#39;&#39;&gt;
&lt;img src=&#39;/files/2016/10/upgrade-18.jpg&#39; alt=&#39;&#39; class=&#39;img-responsive img-thumbnail&#39; itemprop=&#39;contentUrl&#39;&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Have a lot of fun!&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you did everything up to here, now your computer is running openSUSE 42.2 Leap.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can see the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.gnu.org/software/grub/&quot;&gt;GRUB&lt;/a&gt; menu, the one that allows you to choose which operating system to boot when the computer turns on (useful especially if you have Windows and Linux installed on the same machine), is already different:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&#39;image no-ads-here text-center&#39; itemscope itemtype=&#39;http://schema.org/ImageObject&#39;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#39;/files/2016/10/upgrade-19.jpg&#39; title=&#39;&#39;&gt;
&lt;img src=&#39;/files/2016/10/upgrade-19.jpg&#39; alt=&#39;&#39; class=&#39;img-responsive img-thumbnail&#39; itemprop=&#39;contentUrl&#39;&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And &lt;em&gt;voilà&lt;/em&gt;! openSUSE Leap 42.2 is installed and ready for use!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&#39;image no-ads-here text-center&#39; itemscope itemtype=&#39;http://schema.org/ImageObject&#39;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#39;/files/2016/10/upgrade-20-en.jpg&#39; title=&#39;&#39;&gt;
&lt;img src=&#39;/files/2016/10/upgrade-20-en.jpg&#39; alt=&#39;&#39; class=&#39;img-responsive img-thumbnail&#39; itemprop=&#39;contentUrl&#39;&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Make sure everything is in place. Now you may return any repositories you removed. Remember to make the appropriate adjustments with respect to the openSUSE version, changing from &lt;code&gt;42.1&lt;/code&gt; to &lt;code&gt;42.2&lt;/code&gt; where necessary. You may also try to install any program that perhaps has been removed during the upgrade.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Remember to regularly &lt;a href=&quot;/en/2016/10/22/keep-your-system-always-up-to-date/&quot;&gt;check for updates&lt;/a&gt; for your new distribution.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you find any difficulty during the upgrade or have any questions, don&amp;#39;t hesitate to comment!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
                <pubDate>Mon, 31 Oct 2016 23:59:59 -0200</pubDate>
                <link>https://kamarada.github.io/en/2016/10/31/how-to-upgrade-from-opensuse-leap-421-to-422/</link>
                <guid isPermaLink="true">https://kamarada.github.io/en/2016/10/31/how-to-upgrade-from-opensuse-leap-421-to-422/</guid>
                
                
                    <category>en</category>
                
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>Keep your system always up to date</title>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;Computer programs, the more amazing they are, are not perfect: they are made by us, mere humans. As time passes, they are improved, be by optimizations, new features or bug fixes. Bugs can be of many kinds, varying from a simple typo or malfunctioning to a security hole that can be used by malicious people to get unauthorized access to your personal files. Therefore, it is important to keep your computer always up to date, using the latest software versions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Fortunately, keeping your Linux system always up to date is easy if you are using &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.opensuse.org/&quot;&gt;openSUSE&lt;/a&gt;. You can get software updates using the graphical user interface (GUI) or the command line interface (CLI).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&#39;image no-ads-here text-center&#39; itemscope itemtype=&#39;http://schema.org/ImageObject&#39;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#39;/files/2016/10/sw-updates.jpg&#39; title=&#39;Source: [OMG! Ubuntu!](http://www.omgubuntu.co.uk/2016/10/why-use-linux-answer-three-short-words)&#39;&gt;
&lt;img src=&#39;/files/2016/10/sw-updates.jpg&#39; alt=&#39;Source: [OMG! Ubuntu!](http://www.omgubuntu.co.uk/2016/10/why-use-linux-answer-three-short-words)&#39; class=&#39;img-responsive img-thumbnail&#39; itemprop=&#39;contentUrl&#39;&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;

&lt;em class=&#39;caption&#39; itemprop=&#39;description&#39;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.omgubuntu.co.uk/2016/10/why-use-linux-answer-three-short-words&quot;&gt;OMG! Ubuntu!&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;/em&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Getting updates using the GUI&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When you turn on your computer and/or connect it to the Internet, openSUSE Linux automatically looks for software updates.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If it finds updates to be installed, it notifies you:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&#39;image no-ads-here text-center&#39; itemscope itemtype=&#39;http://schema.org/ImageObject&#39;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#39;/files/2016/10/sw-updates-01-en.jpg&#39; title=&#39;&#39;&gt;
&lt;img src=&#39;/files/2016/10/sw-updates-01-en.jpg&#39; alt=&#39;&#39; class=&#39;img-responsive img-thumbnail&#39; itemprop=&#39;contentUrl&#39;&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It just notifies you, leaving you free to decide when to actually update.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When you find an opportune time to download and install updates, click on the &lt;strong&gt;Software Updates&lt;/strong&gt; icon. It will be showing a red X, indicating that your system is not fully updated (that is, there are updates that need to be installed):&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&#39;image no-ads-here text-center&#39; itemscope itemtype=&#39;http://schema.org/ImageObject&#39;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#39;/files/2016/10/sw-updates-02-en.jpg&#39; title=&#39;&#39;&gt;
&lt;img src=&#39;/files/2016/10/sw-updates-02-en.jpg&#39; alt=&#39;&#39; class=&#39;img-responsive img-thumbnail&#39; itemprop=&#39;contentUrl&#39;&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Click on &lt;strong&gt;Install Updates&lt;/strong&gt;. openSUSE will start to fetch updates.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can check the update progress:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&#39;image no-ads-here text-center&#39; itemscope itemtype=&#39;http://schema.org/ImageObject&#39;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#39;/files/2016/10/sw-updates-03-en.jpg&#39; title=&#39;&#39;&gt;
&lt;img src=&#39;/files/2016/10/sw-updates-03-en.jpg&#39; alt=&#39;&#39; class=&#39;img-responsive img-thumbnail&#39; itemprop=&#39;contentUrl&#39;&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But you don&amp;#39;t need to monitor it: while updates are being downloaded and installed, you can continue to use your computer as usual.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You are notified when the update process finishes. Normally, you don&amp;#39;t need to do anything else, not even restart your computer. Updates are already applied and you can notice them if you open any program that has been updated.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When it happens that some update needs the computer to be restarted, the system asks you to restart it as soon as possible. Although that&amp;#39;s recommended, you can restart it at your convenience.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To restart your computer, open the &lt;strong&gt;Application Menu&lt;/strong&gt;, mouse over &lt;strong&gt;Power / Session&lt;/strong&gt; and click on &lt;strong&gt;Restart&lt;/strong&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&#39;image no-ads-here text-center&#39; itemscope itemtype=&#39;http://schema.org/ImageObject&#39;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#39;/files/2016/10/restart-kde-en.jpg&#39; title=&#39;&#39;&gt;
&lt;img src=&#39;/files/2016/10/restart-kde-en.jpg&#39; alt=&#39;&#39; class=&#39;img-responsive img-thumbnail&#39; itemprop=&#39;contentUrl&#39;&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It could happen that the system has installed many updates and at the end, instead of notifying it has finished, it asks you to install further updates:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&#39;image no-ads-here text-center&#39; itemscope itemtype=&#39;http://schema.org/ImageObject&#39;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#39;/files/2016/10/sw-updates-04-en.jpg&#39; title=&#39;&#39;&gt;
&lt;img src=&#39;/files/2016/10/sw-updates-04-en.jpg&#39; alt=&#39;&#39; class=&#39;img-responsive img-thumbnail&#39; itemprop=&#39;contentUrl&#39;&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That&amp;#39;s rare, but it can occur if a package depends on another, and its latest version only becomes available after the latest version of its dependency is installed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Keep updating your system until it informs you it is completely up to date:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&#39;image no-ads-here text-center&#39; itemscope itemtype=&#39;http://schema.org/ImageObject&#39;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#39;/files/2016/10/sw-updates-05-en.jpg&#39; title=&#39;&#39;&gt;
&lt;img src=&#39;/files/2016/10/sw-updates-05-en.jpg&#39; alt=&#39;&#39; class=&#39;img-responsive img-thumbnail&#39; itemprop=&#39;contentUrl&#39;&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Another reason that can cause the system to inform you there are further updates available is the occurrence of failure during any update. In that case, updates that failed to be installed return to the list of available updates. If you try to install them again and once more they fail, try to find out what is wrong before trying again.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Getting updates using the CLI&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you prefer the command line interface, you can use the &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.opensuse.org/Portal:Zypper&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;zypper&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; package manager to check for, download and install software updates.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First, you need to log in as root (superuser) issuing the command &lt;code&gt;su&lt;/code&gt;. It asks you the root password, which you must provide to go on.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then, call &lt;strong&gt;zypper&lt;/strong&gt; with &lt;code&gt;zypper ref&lt;/code&gt; (you can think of that command as &lt;em&gt;refresh&lt;/em&gt;). It will retrieve the list of packages available on the Internet:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&#39;image no-ads-here text-center&#39; itemscope itemtype=&#39;http://schema.org/ImageObject&#39;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#39;/files/2016/10/sw-updates-cmd-01-en.jpg&#39; title=&#39;&#39;&gt;
&lt;img src=&#39;/files/2016/10/sw-updates-cmd-01-en.jpg&#39; alt=&#39;&#39; class=&#39;img-responsive img-thumbnail&#39; itemprop=&#39;contentUrl&#39;&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Note that it shows the progress. When it finishes, run &lt;code&gt;zypper up&lt;/code&gt; (&lt;em&gt;update&lt;/em&gt;). &lt;strong&gt;zypper&lt;/strong&gt; will download and install available updates if there are any:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&#39;image no-ads-here text-center&#39; itemscope itemtype=&#39;http://schema.org/ImageObject&#39;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#39;/files/2016/10/sw-updates-cmd-02-en.jpg&#39; title=&#39;&#39;&gt;
&lt;img src=&#39;/files/2016/10/sw-updates-cmd-02-en.jpg&#39; alt=&#39;&#39; class=&#39;img-responsive img-thumbnail&#39; itemprop=&#39;contentUrl&#39;&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It shows what needs to be done to update the system and asks if you agree. The default option is to continue (&lt;strong&gt;y&lt;/strong&gt;). If that&amp;#39;s what you want, you can just hit &lt;strong&gt;Enter&lt;/strong&gt;. Update will begin and &lt;strong&gt;zypper&lt;/strong&gt; will show the update progress:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&#39;image no-ads-here text-center&#39; itemscope itemtype=&#39;http://schema.org/ImageObject&#39;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#39;/files/2016/10/sw-updates-cmd-03-en.jpg&#39; title=&#39;&#39;&gt;
&lt;img src=&#39;/files/2016/10/sw-updates-cmd-03-en.jpg&#39; alt=&#39;&#39; class=&#39;img-responsive img-thumbnail&#39; itemprop=&#39;contentUrl&#39;&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It is possible that packages need to be removed for the system to be updated as a whole. If you notice in the picture above, &lt;strong&gt;zypper&lt;/strong&gt; proposed installing &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.kde.org/applications/graphics/spectacle/&quot;&gt;Spectacle&lt;/a&gt; and removing &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.kde.org/applications/graphics/ksnapshot/&quot;&gt;KSnapshot&lt;/a&gt;. If you google what are those apps, you will find that both can be used to take screen shots (pictures like the above ones) and that indeed &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.kde.org/announcements/announce-applications-15.12.0.php&quot;&gt;KSnapshot was replaced by Spectacle&lt;/a&gt;. So, in that case, we don&amp;#39;t need to worry.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you don&amp;#39;t agree with the changes suggested by &lt;strong&gt;zypper&lt;/strong&gt;, you can cancel the update process by pressing &lt;strong&gt;n&lt;/strong&gt; and then &lt;strong&gt;Enter&lt;/strong&gt;. You can investigate why it is proposing those changes and try again later.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Usually, when the update process finishes, you don&amp;#39;t need to do anything else, not even restart your computer. But note that at the end of this update &lt;strong&gt;zypper&lt;/strong&gt; considered restarting programs that were using files deleted during the update process:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&#39;image no-ads-here text-center&#39; itemscope itemtype=&#39;http://schema.org/ImageObject&#39;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#39;/files/2016/10/sw-updates-cmd-04-en.jpg&#39; title=&#39;&#39;&gt;
&lt;img src=&#39;/files/2016/10/sw-updates-cmd-04-en.jpg&#39; alt=&#39;&#39; class=&#39;img-responsive img-thumbnail&#39; itemprop=&#39;contentUrl&#39;&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In that case, even if &lt;strong&gt;zypper&lt;/strong&gt; has not asked you to restart your computer, as it said the word &amp;quot;restart&amp;quot;, I recommend you to do so. When the system comes back, it will be fresh new and clear, without risk of malfunction.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Make sure you have installed really all the updates available up to now by repeatedly running &lt;code&gt;zypper up&lt;/code&gt; until it says there is nothing to do:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&#39;image no-ads-here text-center&#39; itemscope itemtype=&#39;http://schema.org/ImageObject&#39;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#39;/files/2016/10/sw-updates-cmd-05-en.jpg&#39; title=&#39;&#39;&gt;
&lt;img src=&#39;/files/2016/10/sw-updates-cmd-05-en.jpg&#39; alt=&#39;&#39; class=&#39;img-responsive img-thumbnail&#39; itemprop=&#39;contentUrl&#39;&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That is, it is not possible to update the system further, because there are no more updates available: your system is really up to date.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Remember to check for software updates from time to time using the &lt;code&gt;zypper ref&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;zypper dup&lt;/code&gt; commands, as the command line interface does not notify you when there are updates available.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
                <pubDate>Sat, 22 Oct 2016 23:40:00 -0200</pubDate>
                <link>https://kamarada.github.io/en/2016/10/22/keep-your-system-always-up-to-date/</link>
                <guid isPermaLink="true">https://kamarada.github.io/en/2016/10/22/keep-your-system-always-up-to-date/</guid>
                
                
                    <category>en</category>
                
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>What is a LiveCD/DVD/USB?</title>
                <description>&lt;div class=&#39;image no-ads-here text-center&#39; itemscope itemtype=&#39;http://schema.org/ImageObject&#39;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#39;/files/2015/11/livecd.png&#39; title=&#39;&#39;&gt;
&lt;img src=&#39;/files/2015/11/livecd.png&#39; alt=&#39;&#39; class=&#39;img-responsive img-thumbnail&#39; itemprop=&#39;contentUrl&#39;&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A &lt;strong&gt;LiveCD&lt;/strong&gt; is a CD medium which brings a ready-to-use operating system. That system does not need to be installed on the computer&amp;#39;s hard drive to run, it can run directly from the CD: you insert the disk into the drive, turn the computer on and use the system, which comes ready-to-use. It is very similar to the system that is run from the hard drive, which is the most common kind of installation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are also the more recent &lt;strong&gt;LiveDVDs&lt;/strong&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;LiveUSBs&lt;/strong&gt;, which follow the same idea: they are, respectively, DVDs and USB sticks (or memory cards) which bring ready-to-use operating systems. All the explanations here also apply to both LiveDVDs and LiveUSBs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The main advantage of a LiveCD is the unconcern with installation: the system comes ready-to-use on the CD, and using it makes no change to your computer&amp;#39;s hard disk operating system. When you finish using a LiveCD, turn the computer off and eject the disk. The next time you turn your computer on, its main operating system (&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.microsoft.com/en-us/windows&quot;&gt;Windows&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.kernel.org/linux.html&quot;&gt;Linux&lt;/a&gt; or other) will start as usual, as if it was the last one to be used.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That makes LiveCDs ideal for people who want to &lt;strong&gt;get to know, try or occasionally use Linux&lt;/strong&gt;, but are unsure about installing it on their computers (or even do not want to install). It is also possible to use LiveCDs to &lt;strong&gt;install Linux&lt;/strong&gt;. Most Linux distributions offer LiveCDs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.opensuse.org/&quot;&gt;openSUSE&lt;/a&gt; Linux distribution is awesome, but &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.linux.com/news/software/applications/865760-opensuse-leap-421-review-the-most-mature-linux-distribution&quot;&gt;it does not offer official LiveCDs anymore&lt;/a&gt;. Thinking about that, the Linux Kamarada Project built a LiveDVD containing a ready-to-use openSUSE system, which can be downloaded &lt;a href=&quot;/en/download/&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;. Using an &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.opensuse.org/SDB:Live_USB_stick&quot;&gt;appropriate software&lt;/a&gt;, it can also be installed on a flash drive and used as a LiveUSB.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;LiveCDs (and their peers LiveDVDs and LiveUSBs) are good to:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Get to know Linux&lt;/strong&gt;: you can occasionally use Linux to get to know it and learn more about it without the commitment to install it on your computer and use it every day;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Try Linux before installing it on your computer&lt;/strong&gt;: you can check if everything is going to work fine after installation;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Repair your computer&lt;/strong&gt;: since you are not using the operating system installed on your computer, it is easier to perform maintenance actions, such as finding and removing viruses, recovering files deleted by accident, finding hidden or restricted files, resetting the administrator password, testing memory, creating or modifying partitions, solving problems that prevent the computer from turning on, among others (in fact, here I listed many situations in which LiveCDs are useful);&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Use a familiar desktop on an unfamiliar machine&lt;/strong&gt; (especially if you already use Linux on your computer and have a LiveCD from the distribution you use);&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Use the same desktop on many machines&lt;/strong&gt;: useful for those who use many computers and do not want to install the software they need on each computer one by one;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Use with some more freedom a restricted computer&lt;/strong&gt; (from university or work, for example): while using a LiveCD system, you can install programs and change settings (note that some restrictions may still apply, such as blocked websites);&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Safely use a computer which in principle is not safe or lacks privacy&lt;/strong&gt;: the LiveCD system does not leave data on the computer (there are even &lt;a href=&quot;https://tails.boum.org/index.en.html&quot;&gt;distributions focused on privacy&lt;/a&gt;);&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Show off Linux&lt;/strong&gt;: if you enjoy Linux, you can use LiveCDs to show it to people on their own machines without installing.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A LiveUSB has one advantage over a LiveCD or LiveDVD: it stores changes to the system (software installed by the user, for example) on the USB stick, so they remain the next time the system is started from the USB stick. That makes LiveUSBs a little closer to traditional systems installed on hard disks. Note that storing system changes is not possible using a CD or DVD, because there is no way to write changes to those media.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Certainly there are other situations in which a LiveCD can be a very powerful tool. Even if you do not want to know Linux deeply or install it on your computer, I recommend that you always have a LiveCD by near: one day, it can be a good troubleshooter!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Disadvantages&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;LiveCDs, as well as LiveDVDs, allow making changes to the system (installing software, for example) because they use part of the RAM memory to store those changes while the system is being used. Therefore, it is not possible to install many software packages. On a LiveUSB, it is possible to install more packages, according to the USB stick capacity.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Also it is important to note that systems run from CDs, DVDs and flash drives are slower than the traditional hard disk systems, because hard disks are faster than those media.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, in general, Live media (LiveCDs, LiveDVDs and LiveUSBs) are &lt;strong&gt;not recommended for everyday use&lt;/strong&gt;. If you want to use Linux every day, consider installing it on your computer or on a virtual machine.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
                <pubDate>Wed, 09 Dec 2015 19:00:00 -0200</pubDate>
                <link>https://kamarada.github.io/en/2015/12/09/what-is-a-livecd-dvd-usb/</link>
                <guid isPermaLink="true">https://kamarada.github.io/en/2015/12/09/what-is-a-livecd-dvd-usb/</guid>
                
                
                    <category>en</category>
                
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>openSUSE Leap 42.1 Becomes First Hybrid Distribution</title>
                <description>&lt;h2&gt;Bridging Community and Enterprise&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The wait is over and a new era begins for openSUSE releases. Contributors, friends and fans can now download the first Linux hybrid distro openSUSE Leap 42.1. Since the last release, exactly one year ago, openSUSE transformed its development process to create an entirely new type of hybrid Linux distribution called openSUSE Leap.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&#39;image no-ads-here text-center&#39; itemscope itemtype=&#39;http://schema.org/ImageObject&#39;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#39;/files/2015/11/Leap-green.png&#39; title=&#39;&#39;&gt;
&lt;img src=&#39;/files/2015/11/Leap-green.png&#39; alt=&#39;&#39; class=&#39;img-responsive img-thumbnail&#39; itemprop=&#39;contentUrl&#39; style=&quot;max-width: 150px;&quot;&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Version 42.1 is the first version of openSUSE Leap that uses source from SUSE Linux Enterprise (SLE) providing a level of stability that will prove to be unmatched by other Linux distributions. Bonding community development and enterprise reliability provides more cohesion for the project and its contributor’s maintenance updates. openSUSE Leap will benefit from the enterprise maintenance effort and will have some of the same packages and updates as SLE, which is different from previous openSUSE versions that created separate maintenance streams.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Community developers provide an equal level of contribution to Leap and upstream projects to the release, which bridges a gap between matured packages and newer packages found in openSUSE’s other distribution Tumbleweed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Since the move was such a shift from previous versions, a new version number and version naming strategy was adapted to reflect the change. The SLE sources come from SUSE’s soon to be released SLE 12 Service Pack 1 (SP1). The naming strategy is SLE 12 SP1 or 12.1 + 30 = openSUSE Leap 42.1. Many have asked why 42, but SUSE and openSUSE have a tradition of starting big ideas with a four and two, a reference to The Hitchhiker’s Guide to the Galaxy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Every minor version of openSUSE Leap users can expect a new KDE and GNOME, but today is all about openSUSE Leap 42.1, so if you are tired of a brown desktop, try a green one.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Have a lot of fun!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;openSUSE Leap 42.1 is…&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;div class=&#39;row&#39;&gt;
&lt;div class=&#39;col-sm-2&#39;&gt;
&lt;div class=&#39;image no-ads-here text-center&#39; itemscope itemtype=&#39;http://schema.org/ImageObject&#39;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#39;/assets/icons/oxygen/48x48/places/favorites.png&#39; title=&#39;&#39;&gt;
&lt;img src=&#39;/assets/icons/oxygen/48x48/places/favorites.png&#39; alt=&#39;&#39; class=&#39;img-responsive img-thumbnail&#39; itemprop=&#39;contentUrl&#39;&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&#39;col-sm-10&#39;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;purposeful&quot;&gt;Purposeful&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Leap provides a balance between new and innovative and mature and downgraded.. Leap offers that enterprise feel, provides modern hardware support and has intentional downgraded packages to reinforce the Long-Term-Support vision of Leap.Newer releases like KDE Plasma 5 and Libreoffice 5 are in Leap while other mature releases like GNOME 3.16 and GNU Compiler Collection 4.8.5 with the option of GCC 5.2 are in Leap as well.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&#39;row&#39;&gt;
&lt;div class=&#39;col-sm-2&#39;&gt;
&lt;div class=&#39;image no-ads-here text-center&#39; itemscope itemtype=&#39;http://schema.org/ImageObject&#39;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#39;/assets/icons/oxygen/48x48/places/start-here-branding.png&#39; title=&#39;&#39;&gt;
&lt;img src=&#39;/assets/icons/oxygen/48x48/places/start-here-branding.png&#39; alt=&#39;&#39; class=&#39;img-responsive img-thumbnail&#39; itemprop=&#39;contentUrl&#39;&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&#39;col-sm-10&#39;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;dependable&quot;&gt;Dependable&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Leap has a further developed Btrfs filesystem as the default option and an XFS data file system for performance, but there are several other options to choose from. The benefit of Btrfs allows users to take advantage of Snapper. Users can recover the previous status of the system using snapshots. Snapper will automatically create hourly snapshots of the system, as well as pre- and post-snapshots for YaST and zypper transactions, which can be disabled. This new version adds the ability to boot right into a snapshot to recover from corruption of important files on the system (like bash). A powerful system and a powerful tool.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Get Leap!&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Downloads of openSUSE Leap 42.1 can be found at &lt;a href=&quot;http://software.opensuse.org/&quot;&gt;software.opensuse.org&lt;/a&gt;. We recommend checking out the &lt;a href=&quot;http://doc.opensuse.org/release-notes/x86_64/openSUSE/Leap/42.1/RELEASE-NOTES.en_GB.html&quot;&gt;Release Notes&lt;/a&gt; before upgrade or installation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Users currently running openSUSE 13.2 can &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.opensuse.org/Upgrade&quot;&gt;upgrade to openSUSE Leap 42.1 via the instructions at this link&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Check out ARM images at &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.opensuse.org/Portal:ARM&quot;&gt;the ARM wiki&lt;/a&gt;. Stable Leap based images for ARMv7 and ARMv8 (AArch64) are there and will receive full maintenance alongside Leap. ARMv6 port is experimental and offers no guarantee.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Thanks!&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;openSUSE Leap 42.1 represents the combined effort of thousands of developers who participate in our distributions and projects shipped with it. The contributors, inside and outside the openSUSE Project, should be proud of this release, and they deserve a major &lt;strong&gt;&amp;quot;thank you&amp;quot;&lt;/strong&gt; for all of the hard work and care that have gone into it. We believe Leap is a great release and will be a Linux distribution developers, sysadmins and users can depend upon! We hope you have a lot of fun using it, and we look forward to working with you on the next release!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;For Developers&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;div class=&#39;row&#39;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#39;col-sm-4&#39;&gt;&lt;div class=&#39;image no-ads-here text-center&#39; itemscope itemtype=&#39;http://schema.org/ImageObject&#39;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#39;/files/2015/11/gnome-builder.png&#39; title=&#39;GNOME Builder&#39;&gt;
&lt;img src=&#39;/files/2015/11/gnome-builder.png&#39; alt=&#39;GNOME Builder&#39; class=&#39;img-responsive img-thumbnail&#39; itemprop=&#39;contentUrl&#39;&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;

&lt;em class=&#39;caption&#39; itemprop=&#39;description&#39;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;GNOME Builder&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;/em&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#39;col-sm-4&#39;&gt;&lt;div class=&#39;image no-ads-here text-center&#39; itemscope itemtype=&#39;http://schema.org/ImageObject&#39;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#39;/files/2015/11/kde-anjunta.png&#39; title=&#39;KDE Anjunta&#39;&gt;
&lt;img src=&#39;/files/2015/11/kde-anjunta.png&#39; alt=&#39;KDE Anjunta&#39; class=&#39;img-responsive img-thumbnail&#39; itemprop=&#39;contentUrl&#39;&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em class=&#39;caption&#39; itemprop=&#39;description&#39;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;KDE Anjunta&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#39;col-sm-4&#39;&gt;&lt;div class=&#39;image no-ads-here text-center&#39; itemscope itemtype=&#39;http://schema.org/ImageObject&#39;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#39;/files/2015/11/kde-qt5-designer.png&#39; title=&#39;KDE Qt5 designer&#39;&gt;
&lt;img src=&#39;/files/2015/11/kde-qt5-designer.png&#39; alt=&#39;KDE Qt5 designer&#39; class=&#39;img-responsive img-thumbnail&#39; itemprop=&#39;contentUrl&#39;&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em class=&#39;caption&#39; itemprop=&#39;description&#39;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;KDE Qt5 designer&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&#39;row&#39;&gt;
&lt;div class=&#39;col-sm-2&#39;&gt;
&lt;div class=&#39;image no-ads-here text-center&#39; itemscope itemtype=&#39;http://schema.org/ImageObject&#39;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#39;/assets/icons/oxygen/48x48/categories/applications-development.png&#39; title=&#39;&#39;&gt;
&lt;img src=&#39;/assets/icons/oxygen/48x48/categories/applications-development.png&#39; alt=&#39;&#39; class=&#39;img-responsive img-thumbnail&#39; itemprop=&#39;contentUrl&#39;&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&#39;col-sm-10&#39;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;ides-and-tooling&quot;&gt;IDEs and tooling&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Leap carries the latest version of the Qt 5 GUI toolkit (5.5). Qt5.5 brings multiple features and enhancements for developers, but also for normal users, who will benefit from a large improvement in multi-screen handling and in QML (which is heavily used by Plasma). Builder is a brand new IDE, which is intended to make it easy to create GNOME applications. This initial 3.16 release is an early preview, which shows editing features, such as split view, snippets, auto-indentation and a VIM engine. Builder was backed by a successful crowdfunding campaign early in 2015, and there are big plans for the future. These include project management functionality, global search, version tracking, debugging, Glade integration, and much more.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&#39;row&#39;&gt;
&lt;div class=&#39;col-sm-2&#39;&gt;
&lt;div class=&#39;image no-ads-here text-center&#39; itemscope itemtype=&#39;http://schema.org/ImageObject&#39;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#39;/assets/icons/oxygen/48x48/categories/applications-engineering.png&#39; title=&#39;&#39;&gt;
&lt;img src=&#39;/assets/icons/oxygen/48x48/categories/applications-engineering.png&#39; alt=&#39;&#39; class=&#39;img-responsive img-thumbnail&#39; itemprop=&#39;contentUrl&#39;&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&#39;col-sm-10&#39;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;languages-and-libraries&quot;&gt;Languages and Libraries&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The KDE Frameworks 5 development libraries are at the latest stable version at the time of release (5.15), bringing in many bugfixes which affect the many KDE applications that are using them. In particular, the Baloo file indexing framework has been the subject of much changes, from bugfixes to performance improvements.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;For Sysadmins&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;div class=&#39;row&#39;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#39;col-sm-4&#39;&gt;&lt;div class=&#39;image no-ads-here text-center&#39; itemscope itemtype=&#39;http://schema.org/ImageObject&#39;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#39;/files/2015/11/yast-app-folder.png&#39; title=&#39;YaST App Folder&#39;&gt;
&lt;img src=&#39;/files/2015/11/yast-app-folder.png&#39; alt=&#39;YaST App Folder&#39; class=&#39;img-responsive img-thumbnail&#39; itemprop=&#39;contentUrl&#39;&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;

&lt;em class=&#39;caption&#39; itemprop=&#39;description&#39;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;YaST App Folder&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;/em&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#39;col-sm-4&#39;&gt;&lt;div class=&#39;image no-ads-here text-center&#39; itemscope itemtype=&#39;http://schema.org/ImageObject&#39;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#39;/files/2015/11/installation-overview.png&#39; title=&#39;Installation overview&#39;&gt;
&lt;img src=&#39;/files/2015/11/installation-overview.png&#39; alt=&#39;Installation overview&#39; class=&#39;img-responsive img-thumbnail&#39; itemprop=&#39;contentUrl&#39;&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em class=&#39;caption&#39; itemprop=&#39;description&#39;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Installation overview&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#39;col-sm-4&#39;&gt;&lt;div class=&#39;image no-ads-here text-center&#39; itemscope itemtype=&#39;http://schema.org/ImageObject&#39;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#39;/files/2015/11/yast.png&#39; title=&#39;YaST&#39;&gt;
&lt;img src=&#39;/files/2015/11/yast.png&#39; alt=&#39;YaST&#39; class=&#39;img-responsive img-thumbnail&#39; itemprop=&#39;contentUrl&#39;&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em class=&#39;caption&#39; itemprop=&#39;description&#39;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;YaST&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&#39;row&#39;&gt;
&lt;div class=&#39;col-sm-2&#39;&gt;
&lt;div class=&#39;image no-ads-here text-center&#39; itemscope itemtype=&#39;http://schema.org/ImageObject&#39;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#39;/assets/icons/hicolor/64x64/apps/yast-virtualisation.png&#39; title=&#39;&#39;&gt;
&lt;img src=&#39;/assets/icons/hicolor/64x64/apps/yast-virtualisation.png&#39; alt=&#39;&#39; class=&#39;img-responsive img-thumbnail&#39; itemprop=&#39;contentUrl&#39;&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&#39;col-sm-10&#39;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;virtualization&quot;&gt;Virtualization&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;openSUSE Leap 42.1 is full of virtualization solutions. QEMU 2.3.1, VirtualBox 5.0.6 and Docker 1.8.2 makes openSUSE Leap 42.1 a perfect base system to distribute applications. Set up is easy with YaST, so you’ll be able deploy solutions quickly and easily. GNOME boxes, virt-manager, and virsh are also useful to sysadmins using openSUSE.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&#39;row&#39;&gt;
&lt;div class=&#39;col-sm-2&#39;&gt;
&lt;div class=&#39;image no-ads-here text-center&#39; itemscope itemtype=&#39;http://schema.org/ImageObject&#39;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#39;/assets/icons/hicolor/48x48/apps/yast.png&#39; title=&#39;&#39;&gt;
&lt;img src=&#39;/assets/icons/hicolor/48x48/apps/yast.png&#39; alt=&#39;&#39; class=&#39;img-responsive img-thumbnail&#39; itemprop=&#39;contentUrl&#39;&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&#39;col-sm-10&#39;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;improved-yast&quot;&gt;Improved YaST&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Being a completely open source project, the YaST versions and features shipped with SLE and openSUSE has always being in pretty close sync. With Leap that trends goes one step further, since 42.1 it will include exactly the same version of YaST, AutoYaST and Linuxrc that will be shipped in SLE12-SP1. When compared to the versions shipped in openSUSE 13.2, that means more than 600 fixes including corrections of errors, new features and enhancements in the already existing ones. Users and sysadmins will benefit from the improved YaST included in Leap 42.1. YaST is now more developer friendly than ever, with more polished code (although there is still a lot of autoconverted code from YCP), better development tools and documentation and a much better integration into the Ruby ecosystem including RSpec helpers, Rake tasks and other goodies. Although the YaST2-lxc module was dropped, the YaST family has grown with the addition of three new modules. Read more about the &lt;a href=&quot;https://news.opensuse.org/2015/02/25/openness-brings-fresh-air-to-yast/&quot;&gt;new modules&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&#39;row&#39;&gt;
&lt;div class=&#39;col-sm-2&#39;&gt;
&lt;div class=&#39;image no-ads-here text-center&#39; itemscope itemtype=&#39;http://schema.org/ImageObject&#39;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#39;/files/2015/11/machinery.png&#39; title=&#39;&#39;&gt;
&lt;img src=&#39;/files/2015/11/machinery.png&#39; alt=&#39;&#39; class=&#39;img-responsive img-thumbnail&#39; itemprop=&#39;contentUrl&#39;&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&#39;col-sm-10&#39;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;machinery&quot;&gt;Machinery&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Available for use with openSUSE Leap 42.1 is &lt;a href=&quot;http://machinery-project.org/&quot;&gt;Machinery&lt;/a&gt;. Machinery is a command line application sysadmins can use for creating descriptions of Linux systems and working with them. You can use it to get insight into existing systems, to store and track their state, or to create new systems based on existing ones. Machinery provides powerful views of individual and comparisons between systems. It can also export descriptions to other tools for installation, migration, image building, containerization, or cloud deployment, and provides defined interfaces to work with system descriptions from your custom tools.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;For Users&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;div class=&#39;row&#39;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#39;col-sm-4&#39;&gt;&lt;div class=&#39;image no-ads-here text-center&#39; itemscope itemtype=&#39;http://schema.org/ImageObject&#39;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#39;/files/2015/11/libreoffice5.png&#39; title=&#39;GNOME LibreOffice 5&#39;&gt;
&lt;img src=&#39;/files/2015/11/libreoffice5.png&#39; alt=&#39;GNOME LibreOffice 5&#39; class=&#39;img-responsive img-thumbnail&#39; itemprop=&#39;contentUrl&#39;&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;

&lt;em class=&#39;caption&#39; itemprop=&#39;description&#39;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;GNOME LibreOffice 5&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;/em&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#39;col-sm-4&#39;&gt;&lt;div class=&#39;image no-ads-here text-center&#39; itemscope itemtype=&#39;http://schema.org/ImageObject&#39;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#39;/files/2015/11/gnome-weather.png&#39; title=&#39;GNOME Weather&#39;&gt;
&lt;img src=&#39;/files/2015/11/gnome-weather.png&#39; alt=&#39;GNOME Weather&#39; class=&#39;img-responsive img-thumbnail&#39; itemprop=&#39;contentUrl&#39;&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em class=&#39;caption&#39; itemprop=&#39;description&#39;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;GNOME Weather&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#39;col-sm-4&#39;&gt;&lt;div class=&#39;image no-ads-here text-center&#39; itemscope itemtype=&#39;http://schema.org/ImageObject&#39;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#39;/files/2015/11/gimp.png&#39; title=&#39;GIMP in Plasma 5&#39;&gt;
&lt;img src=&#39;/files/2015/11/gimp.png&#39; alt=&#39;GIMP in Plasma 5&#39; class=&#39;img-responsive img-thumbnail&#39; itemprop=&#39;contentUrl&#39;&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em class=&#39;caption&#39; itemprop=&#39;description&#39;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;GIMP in Plasma 5&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&#39;row&#39;&gt;
&lt;div class=&#39;col-sm-2&#39;&gt;
&lt;div class=&#39;image no-ads-here text-center&#39; itemscope itemtype=&#39;http://schema.org/ImageObject&#39;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#39;/assets/icons/oxygen/48x48/apps/kde.png&#39; title=&#39;&#39;&gt;
&lt;img src=&#39;/assets/icons/oxygen/48x48/apps/kde.png&#39; alt=&#39;&#39; class=&#39;img-responsive img-thumbnail&#39; itemprop=&#39;contentUrl&#39;&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&#39;col-sm-10&#39;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;kde&quot;&gt;KDE&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;openSUSE Leap 42.1 is the first stable openSUSE release to include KDE Plasma 5 (version 5.4.2) as the default desktop environment. Plasma 5 is now mature enough for a wide audience to enjoy this beautiful, feature rich, innovative and performant desktop. The 5.4 version of the workspace introduces a new audio volume applet, a full-screen dashboard menu, many new icons (more than 1600 added) and improved High DPI support. Some minor “papercuts” from the previous releases have also been fixed, for example additional date formats in the clock or improvements in Folder View behavior and visuals.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&#39;row&#39;&gt;
&lt;div class=&#39;col-sm-2&#39;&gt;
&lt;div class=&#39;image no-ads-here text-center&#39; itemscope itemtype=&#39;http://schema.org/ImageObject&#39;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#39;/assets/icons/hicolor/48x48/apps/pattern-gnome.png&#39; title=&#39;&#39;&gt;
&lt;img src=&#39;/assets/icons/hicolor/48x48/apps/pattern-gnome.png&#39; alt=&#39;&#39; class=&#39;img-responsive img-thumbnail&#39; itemprop=&#39;contentUrl&#39;&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&#39;col-sm-10&#39;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;gnome&quot;&gt;GNOME&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;openSUSE Leap 42.1 ships with GNOME 3.16.2. The GNOME 3.16.x branch has been released in April 2015 and received multiple bug fix iterations, making it a well tested and stable version to supplement the rock-solid SLE12 base system. GNOME 3’s visuals have been updated for 3.16. The Activities Overview, login screen, system menus and other system components have been given a new, more contemporary look. The new visuals are designed to integrate with the visual style of GNOME applications, for a more seamless experience. 3.16 has a new style of scrollbar for GNOME 3. Instead of being shown all the time, these new overlay scrollbars are only shown when needed: a small scroll indicator is shown when the pointer is moved, and a larger bar appears when control is wanted.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&#39;row&#39;&gt;
&lt;div class=&#39;col-sm-2&#39;&gt;
&lt;div class=&#39;image no-ads-here text-center&#39; itemscope itemtype=&#39;http://schema.org/ImageObject&#39;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#39;/assets/icons/oxygen/48x48/places/user-desktop.png&#39; title=&#39;&#39;&gt;
&lt;img src=&#39;/assets/icons/oxygen/48x48/places/user-desktop.png&#39; alt=&#39;&#39; class=&#39;img-responsive img-thumbnail&#39; itemprop=&#39;contentUrl&#39;&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&#39;col-sm-10&#39;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;other-desktop-environments&quot;&gt;Other desktop environments&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;openSUSE Leap 42.1 includes MATE (1.10), which provides support for both GTK2 and GTK3 toolkits, added support for 3.x GUI toolkits and improvements in Audio Mixer Library. openSUSE Leap 42.1 also ships with XFCE (4.12.1). The XFCE panel can now intelligently hide itself, supports GTK3 plugins, and saw lots of its third-party plugins updated to take full advantage of the features added in 4.10. Enlightenment 19 (0.19.12) ships in openSUSE Leap 42.1 and can now unshade clients when they’re activated, updates the X11 compositor to use damage events, and updates the icon theme search list for the wizard.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Details about Power 8 (ppc64le), and ARM (AArch64) in openSUSE Leap 42.1 will be released at a later date.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;About the openSUSE Project&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The openSUSE Project is a worldwide community that promotes the use of Linux everywhere. It creates one of the world’s best Linux distributions, working together in an open, transparent and friendly manner as part of the worldwide Free and Open Source Software community. The project is controlled by its community and relies on the contributions of individuals, working as testers, writers, translators, usability experts, artists and ambassadors or developers. The project embraces a wide variety of technology, people with different levels of expertise, speaking different languages and having different cultural backgrounds. Learn more about it on &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.opensuse.org/&quot;&gt;opensuse.org&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;This news was originally published by &lt;a href=&quot;https://news.opensuse.org/author/ddemaio/&quot;&gt;Douglas DeMaio&lt;/a&gt; at &lt;a href=&quot;https://news.opensuse.org/2015/11/04/opensuse-leap-42-1-becomes-first-hybrid-distribution/&quot;&gt;news.opensuse.org&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
                <pubDate>Wed, 04 Nov 2015 08:00:00 -0200</pubDate>
                <link>https://kamarada.github.io/en/2015/11/04/opensuse-leap-42-1-becomes-first-hybrid-distribution/</link>
                <guid isPermaLink="true">https://kamarada.github.io/en/2015/11/04/opensuse-leap-42-1-becomes-first-hybrid-distribution/</guid>
                
                
                    <category>en</category>
                
            </item>
        
    </channel>
</rss>
